4K资源来源:Hao4k影音
-专注4K家庭影音, 服务千万发烧友-
更多4K蓝光原盘:www.Hao4k.vip
教 父
我信仰美国
I believe in America.
美国让我发了财
America has made my fortune...
而且我按美国方式教养我的女儿
and I raised my daughter in the American fashion.
我给了她自由，但是…
I give her freedom, but...
我教导她永远不要有辱家门
I taught her never to dishonor her family.
她找了个男友，不是意大利人
She found a boyfriend. Not an Italian.
她跟他去看电影
She went to the movies with him.
她在外面待很晚
She stayed out late.
我没有反对
I didn't protest.
两个月前，他带她去兜风
Two months ago, he took her for a drive...
还有另一个男孩
with another boyfriend.
他们灌她喝威士忌
They made her drink whiskey...
然后，他们想要占她便宜
and then they tried to take advantage of her.
她反抗了
She resisted.
她保住了她的名节
She kept her honor.
于是他们打她，像是打动物
So they beat her like an animal.
等我去到医院，她的鼻梁断了
When I went to the hospital, her nose was broken...
她的下巴被打碎了
her jaw was shattered...
用钢丝固定起来
held together by wire.
因为疼痛，她甚至不能哭泣
She couldn't even weep because of the pain.
但我哭了
But I wept.
我为什么哭呢？
Why did I weep?
她是我生命之光
She was the light of my life.
美丽的女孩
Beautiful girl.
现在她再也不会美丽了
Now she will never be beautiful again.
对不起
Sorry.
我…我去找警察，像个本分的美国人那样
I went to the police like a good American.
那两个男孩被带去审判
These two boys were brought to trial.
法官判他们坐牢三年，缓期执行
A judge sentence them to three years in prison...and suspend their sentence.
缓期执行
Suspended sentence.
他们当天就获得自由
They went free that very day.
我像个傻瓜似的站在法庭上
I stood in the courtroom like a fool.
而那两个杂种，竟朝着我笑
And those two bastard, they smiled at me.
于是我对我妻子说
Then I said to my wife
“为求公道，我们必须去找唐・柯利昂尼”
"For justice we must go to Don Corleone."
你干嘛去找警察？你干嘛不先来找我？
Why did you go to the police? Why didn't you come to me first?
你要我做什么？
What do you want of me?
尽管吩咐，但一定要做我恳求你做的事
Tell me anything, but do what I beg you to do.
什么事？
What is that?
那我办不到
That I cannot do.
你要什么  我都会给你
I'll give you anything you ask.
我们相识多年，但这是你第一次来找我咨询帮忙
We've known each other many years, but this is the first time you ever came to me for counsel or for help.
我都记不起上回是什么时候……
I can't remember the last time that...
你请我到你家去喝杯咖啡
you invited me to your house for a cup of coffee.
虽然我妻子是你独生女的教母
even though my wife is godmother to your only child.
咱们坦白说吧
But let's be frank here.
你从来不想要我的友谊
You never wanted my friendship...
而且…你害怕欠我人情
and you were afraid to be in my debt.
我不想惹上麻烦
I didn't want to get into trouble.
我理解
I understand.
你在美国发现了乐园
You found paradise in America.
你有一门好生意，过上了好生活
You had a good trade, made a good living.
警察保护你，而且还有法院
Police protected you, and there were courts of law.
你不需要我这种朋友
So you didn't need a friend like me.
但是，现在你来找我说
But now you come to me and you say...
“唐・柯利昂尼，给我公道”
"Don Corleone, give me justice."
但你提要求时并无敬意
But you don't ask with respect.
你没有献上友谊
You don't offer friendship.
你甚至没想叫我“教父”
You don't even think to call me "Godfather."
相反，你来到我家，在我女儿出嫁这天
Instead, you come into my house...on the day my daughter is to be married...
你还要求我去杀人，为了钱
and you ask me to do murder for money.
我要求你主持公道
I ask you for justice.
那不是公道，你女儿还活着
That is not justice. Your daughter is still alive.
那么他们一定得受罪，如同她一样
They must suffer then, as she suffers.
我应该付你多少钱？
How much shall I pay you?
博纳塞拉  博纳塞拉
Bonasera. Bonasera.
到底我做了什么让你待我如此不尊重？
What have I ever done to make you treat me so disrespectfully?
如果你带着友谊来找我
If you'd come to me in friendship...
那么毁了你女儿的渣滓当天就会遭难
then the scum that ruined your daughter would be suffering this very day.
而且如果你这种诚实人偶尔树敌
And if, by chance an honest man like yourself should make enemies...
那么他们就会成为我的敌人
then they would become my enemies.
这样他们就会害怕你
And then they would fear you.
做我的朋友？
Be my friend?
教父
Godfather.
很好
Good.
有一天，这一天也许永远不会到来…
Someday, and that day may never come...
我会打电话要你为我效一次劳
I'll call upon you to do a service for me.
但在那一天到来之前
But until that day...
收下这份公道，当做我女儿结婚这天的一份礼物吧
accept this justice as a gift on my daughter's wedding day.
- 谢谢[意大利语]教父  - 别客气[意大利语]
- Gràzie, Godfather. - Prego
这件事交给… 克里门萨
Give this to Clemenza.
我要用可靠的人，不会冲动的人
I want reliable people, people that aren't going to be carried away.
我说，我们不是杀人犯，不管这位殡葬人怎么说
I mean, we're not murderers... in spite of what this undertaker says.
- 迈克尔在哪里？  - 什么？别担心，还早呢，他会来的
- Where's Michael? - What? Don't worry. It's early. He'll be here.
没有迈克尔我们不照相
We're not taking the picture without Michael.
（意大利语）
- 怎么回事，桑尼？  - 是迈克尔的事
-What's the matter, Sonny? -It's Michael.
唐・巴茨尼
Don Barzini.
（意大利语）
喂，泡利，给我点酒
Hey, Paulie! Let me have some wine.
泡利，再来些酒
Paulie! More wine.
对不起[意大利语]，给
Scusi, please.
- 啊，你看起来棒极了 - 你算什么？舞蹈裁判吗？
- Ah, you look "terrif" on the floor. - What are you, a dance judge or something?
（意大利语）
去小区里转转，做好你的工作
Go take a walk around the neighborhood. Do your job.
桑德拉，帮个忙，看住孩子们，别让他们乱跑，好吗？
Hey, Sandra, come on, do me a favor. Watch the kids. Don't let 'em run wild, all right?
噢，你看好你自己，好吗？
You watch yourself, all right?
两三万，小额现钞
Twenty or thirty grand. In small bills, cash.
在那个小丝袋里
In that little silk purse.
如果这是别人的婚礼…真不幸[意大利语]
If this was somebody else's wedding. Sfortunato!
泡利，我这儿有两个gobbagool，gabagol还有熏火腿
Hey, Paulie! I got two gobbagool... gabagol and a prosciutto.
…蠢货
Stupid jerk!
喂，怎么回事？
Hey, what's the matter?
- 我得回去工作了 - 汤姆
- Have to go back to work. - Oh, Tom.
这是婚礼的一部分
It's part of the wedding.
没有西西里人在女儿结婚那天 能拒绝任何的请求
No Sicilian can refuse any request on his daughter's wedding day.
唐・柯利昂尼，我十分荣幸并感激你邀请我到你家
Don Corleone, I am honored and grateful that you have invited me to your home
你们在干什么？滚开
What're you doing? Get outta here.
这是私人宴会，快走
This is a private party. Go on.
这算什么？喂，我妹妹的婚礼
What is it? Hey, my sister's wedding.
该死的FBI，什么都不尊重
Goddamn FBI don't respect nothin'.
喂，过来，过来过来，给你
Hey, come here, come here. Come here! There.
但是快结束时，他被假释去帮助美国战时生产
But towards the end he was paroled to help with the American war effort.
所以过去六个月他在我的糕饼店做事
So for the last six months, he's been working at my pastry shop.
纳佐林，我的朋友，我能为你做什么？
Nazorine, my friend, what can I do for you?
现在战争结束了
Now that the war is over...
这个男孩恩佐，他们要把他遣返意大利
this boy, Enzo, they want to repatriate him back to Italy.
教父，我有个女儿
Godfather, I have a daughter.
你看，她和恩佐…
See, she and Enzo--
你要恩佐留在这个国家，和你女儿成亲
You want Enzo to stay in this country and you want your daughter to be married.
你什么都了解
You understand everything.
黑根先生，谢谢
Mr. Hagen. Thank you.
等着瞧我为你女儿做的漂亮结婚蛋糕
And wait till you see the beautiful wedding cake I made for your daughter.
这么高… 还有新娘新郎和天使…
Like this, with the bride and the groom and the angles--
- 这件事我该交给谁去办？ - 不要给我们的人
- Who should I give this job to? - Not to our paisan.
给别的区的犹太众议员
Give it to a Jew congressman in another district.
名单上还有谁？
Who else is on the list?
- 哟  - 嗨，迈克尔，你好吗
-Yo -Hey, Michael. How are you?
你好
Hello.
他不在名单上，但卢卡・布拉西想要见你
He's not on the list, but Luca Brasi wants to see you.
这个…有这个必要吗？
Is this...Is this necessary?
他没料到会受邀参加婚礼，所以要向你致谢
He didn't expect to be invited to the wedding so he wanted to thank you.
好吧
All right.
唐・柯利昂尼，我深感荣幸并感激，你邀请我来到你家
Don Corleone, I am honored and grateful...that you have invited me to your home
在你女儿婚礼这一天
...on the wedding day of your daughter.
祝愿他们第一个孩子是个男孩
And may their first child be a masculine child.
- 阁下…  - 迈克尔
- Don-- - Michael?
唐・柯利昂尼
Don Corleone--
那边那个人在自言自语
That man over there is talking to himself.
看到那边那个吓人的家伙了吗？
See that scary guy over there?
他是个很吓人的家伙
He's a very scary guy.
他是谁？叫什么名字？
Well, who is he? What's his name?
他名叫卢卡・布拉西
His name is Luca Brasi...
他有时候替我父亲办事
and he helps my father out sometimes.
哦，迈克尔，等一下  他过来了
Oh, Michael, wait a minute. He's coming over here.
迈克尔
Michael
汤姆
Tom
你气色好极了
You look terrific!
我哥哥汤姆・黑根  这是凯伊・亚当斯
My brother Tom Hagen. This is Kay Adams.
- 你好吗，汤姆  - 你好吗，幸会
- How do you do, Tom? - How do you do? Nice to meet you.
你父亲一直在问你
Your father's been asking for you.
- 很高兴见到你  - 幸会  - 我会去的，汤姆
- Very nice to meet you. - Nice to meet you. - I'll be there, Tom.
他是你哥哥的话，他为何会有不一样的姓氏？
If he's your brother, why does he have a different name?
哦，我哥哥桑尼小时候…
Oh, eh, when my brother Sonny was a kid...
在街上发现汤姆・黑根，无家可归
he found Tom Hagen in the street, and he had no home.
所以我父亲接纳了他
So my father took him in...
从此他就和我们住在一起了
and he's been with us ever since.
他是个好律师
He's a good lawyer.
不是西西里人，不过…
Not a Sicilian, but...
我想他会当consigliere
I think he's gonna be consigliere.
- 那是什么？  - 那是…
- What's that? - That's...
像是个顾问、建言者，在家族中非常重要
like a counselor, an advisor. Very important to the family.
喜欢这烤宽面吗？
You like your lasagna?
唐・柯利昂尼
Don Corleone
我深感荣幸与感激
I am honored and grateful...
你邀请我来到你女儿的婚礼
that you have invited me to your daughter's wedding...
在令媛结婚的当天
on the day of your daughter's wedding.
我祝愿他们的第一个孩子，是一个男孩
And I hope that their first child...be a masculine child.
我献上我永无止境的忠诚
I pledge my ever-ending loyalty.
给令媛的新娘贺礼
For your daughter's bridal purse.
谢谢你，卢卡，我最珍贵的朋友
Thank you, Luca, my most valued friend.
唐・柯利昂尼，我先告退了，因为我知道你忙
Don Corleone, I'm gonna leave you now... because I know you are busy.
谢谢
Thank you.
柯利昂尼夫人
Signora Corleone
不…
No, no, no.
科利参议员为不能亲自前来而道歉
Senator Cauly apologized for not coming personally...
他说你会谅解的
but said you'd understand.
有些法官也一样
Also some of the judges.
他们都送了礼物
They've all sent gifts.
外面是怎么回事？
What is that outside?
约翰尼
Johnny!
我爱你
I love you.
他大老远从加州赶来参加婚礼
He came all the way from California to come to the wedding.
我告诉过你他会来的
I told you he was going to come.
已经两年了，他也许又有麻烦了
It's been two years. He's probably in trouble again.
他是个好教子
He's a good godson.
约翰尼…唱首歌
Sing a song.
迈克尔，你从未告诉我你认识约翰尼・方廷
Michael, you never told me you knew Johnny Fontane.
- 当然，你想见他吗？  - 啊？是的，当然
-Sure. You wanna meet him? -Huh? Oh, well, sure.
我父亲帮他建立他的事业
My father helped him with his career.
是吗？
He did?
怎么做的？
How?
- 我们听听这首歌  - 不，迈克尔
- Let's listen to the song. - No, Michael
拜托，迈克尔，告诉我
Please, Michael. Tell me.
约翰尼刚出道时 签了一份私人服务合同
When Johnny was first starting out he was signed to this personal service contract
跟一个大乐队的领班
with a big bandleader.
随着他的事业越来越好，他想要摆脱它
And as his career got better and better...he wanted to get out of it.
约翰尼是我父亲的教子
Now, Johnny is my father's godson...
于是…我父亲去见这个乐队领班
and my father went to see this bandleader...
给他开价1万美元，放约翰尼走
and he offered him $10,000 to let Johnny go.
但这个领班说不行
But the bandleader said no.
所以第二天…
So the next day
我父亲再去见他 只是这次带着卢卡・布拉西
my father went to see him...only this time with Luca Brasi.
一个小时之内
And within an hour,
他签了一份解约书
he signed a release...
收下1千美元的保付支票
for a certified check of $1,000.
他怎么办到的？
How'd he do that?
我父亲给他开了个不能拒绝的条件
My father made him an offer he couldn't refuse.
是什么条件？
What was that?
卢卡・布拉西拿一支枪对着他的头
Luca Brasi held a gun to his head...
而我父亲跟他保证…
and my father assured him
要么是他的脑浆，要么是他的签字会落在合同上
that either his brains...or his signature would be on the contract.
这是个真实的故事
That's a true story.
那是我的家庭，凯伊，不是我
That's my family, Kay. It's not me.
谁给我教子来杯酒？
Who get my godson a glass of wine?
我会处理的
I'll take care of it.
汤姆
Tom.
我要你去找桑提诺，叫他到办公室来
I want you to find Santino. Tell him to come to the office.
你好吗，弗雷多？
How are you, Fredo?
弗雷多
Fredo.
我哥哥弗雷多，这位是凯伊・亚当斯
My brother Fredo. This is Kay Adams.
- 嗨  - 你好吗？
- Hi. - How ya doin'?
- 这是我弟弟迈克尔  - 你玩得愉快吗？
- This is my brother Mike. - Are you having a good time?
对，这是你的朋友？
Yeah. This is your friend, huh?
我不知道该怎么办
I don't know what to do.
我的嗓子很弱  很虚弱
My voice is weak. It's weak.
总之，如果我能得到那部电影的那个角色
Anyway, if I had this part in the picture, you know...
它会让我再次回到顶峰
it puts me right back up on top again.
但是这个…
But this...
这个人拦着，他不给我这角色，电影公司的老板
this man out there, he won't give it to me. The head of the studio.
- 他叫什么名字？  - 沃茨，沃茨，他…
- What's his name? - Woltz.
他不愿意给我，他还说没有机会，没有机会
He won't give it to me... and he says there's no chance, no chance.
桑尼？
Sonny?
桑尼，你在里面吗？
Sonny, you in there?
什么事？
What?
老头子要见你
The old man wants to see you.
好，就一分钟
Yeah, one minute.
桑尼
Sonny
一个月以前，他…
A month ago, he...
买下这本书的电影版权，一本畅销书
bought the movie rights to this book. A best-seller.
男主角正好是一个我这样的人，唉…
And the main character is a guy just like me. Why...
我连演都不用演，只要当我自己就行
I wouldn't even have to act. Just be myself.
噢…教父，我不知道该怎么办，我不知道该怎么办
Oh, Godfather, I don't know what to do.
你可以像个男人一样行事
You can act like a man!
你怎么搞的？
What's the matter with you?
你就成了这样一个好莱坞娘炮？
Is this how you turned out? A Hollywood finocchio that...
哭得像个女人？
that cries like a woman?
“我该怎么办？我该怎么办？”
"What can I do?" "What can I do?"
这是什么胡话？
What is that nonsense?
荒唐
Ridiculous!
- 你花时间陪家人吗？  - 我当然有
- You spend time with your family? - Sure I do.
很好
Good.
因为不花时间陪家人的男人，永远成不了真正的男人
Because the man who doesn't spend time with his family can never be a real man.
过来
Come here.
你看来糟透了
You look terrible.
我要你多吃点
I want you to eat.
我要你好好休息，从现在起一个月后，这个…
I want you to rest well, and a month from now this...
好莱坞大亨，会如你所愿的
Hollywood big shot's gonna give you what you want.
太迟了，他们一周内就要开拍了
Too late. They start shooting in a week.
我会给他提一个无法拒绝的条件
I'm gonna make him an offer he can't refuse.
现在到外面去好好玩，还有…
Now just go outside, enjoy yourself and...
- 忘掉这些鬼话吧  - 好的
- forget about all this nonsense. - All right.
听着，我要你全都留给我来办
Listen. I want you to leave it all to me.
好的
All right.
我女儿什么时候跟新郎离开？
What time does my daughter leave with the bridegroom?
切完蛋糕后的几分钟
In a few minutes, right after they cut the cake.
你的新女婿，要给他重要职务吗？
Now, your new son-in-law, we give him something important.
永远不要
Never.
给他个活计，但永远别跟他谈论家族生意
Give him a living but never discuss the family business with him.
还有别的吗？
What else?
维吉尔・索洛佐来过电话
Virgil Sollozzo called.
我们必须给他留出下周某一天来
We have to give him a day sometime next week.
等你从加州回来我们再讨论
We'll discuss him when you come back from California.
我何时去加州？
When am I going to California?
我要你今晚去
I want you to go tonight.
我要你跟这个…
I want you to talk to this...
电影大亨谈谈，解决约翰尼的事
movie big shot and settle this business for Johnny.
要是没有其它事，我要去参加我女儿的婚礼了
If there's nothing else, I'd like to go to my daughter's wedding.
卡洛，我们要拍照了
Carlo, we're gonna take the picture.
等一下
Wait a minute.
不，迈克尔，我不行
No, Michael, not me.
好了，稍微靠近点
Okay, just a little closer.
好了，就是这样，别动
Okay, that's it. Just like that now. Hold it.
好了，开始说吧
All right, start talking.
我是约翰尼・方廷的一个朋友派来的
I was sent by a friend of Johnny Fontane.
这个朋友是我的客户
This friend is my client...
他将给予沃茨先生永恒的友谊
and would give his undying friendship to Mr. Woltz
只要沃茨先生给我们帮个小忙
if Mr. Woltz would grant us a small favor.
沃茨听着呢
Woltz is listening.
把你下周开拍那部战争片里的那个角色给约翰尼
Give Johnny the part in that new war film you're starting next week.
那么…你的朋友会给沃茨先生帮什么忙呢？
And... what favor would your friend grant Mr. Woltz?
你将会有些工会的麻烦，我的客户能消弭它们
You're gonna have some union problems. My client could make them disappear.
另外，你的一个顶级明星刚从大麻改用海洛因了
Also, one of your top stars has just moved from marijuana to heroin.
你是在要挟我吗？
Are you trying to muscle me?
- 绝对没有  - 好了，你听好了
- Absolutely not. - Now, look, listen to me.
你这个油腔滑调的王八蛋
you smooth-talking son of a bitch!
让我跟你和你的老板说清楚，不管他是谁
Let me lay it on the line for you and your boss, whoever he is!
约翰尼・方廷绝对拿不到那部电影
Johnny Fontane will never get that movie.
我不管有多少老西、老意、南欧人什么的冒出来
I don't care how many dago, guinea, wop...greaseball goombahs come outta the woodwork.
我是德裔爱尔兰人
I'm German-Irish.
那我告诉你，德国泡菜老兄
Well, let me tell you something, my kraut mick friend.
我要好好收拾你，你都不知道打击来自何方
I'm ganna make so much trouble for you, you won't know what hit you.
沃茨先生，我是个律师，我不是来威胁…
Mr. Woltz, I'm a lawyer. I have not threatened--
我认识几乎每一个纽约的大律师，你是什么东西？
I know almost every big lawyer in New York. Who the hell are you?
我的执业情况特别，只处理一位客户
I have a special practice. I handle one client.
你有我的电话号码，我等你电话
Now, you have my number. I'll wait for your call.
对了，我很赞赏你的电影
By the way, I admire your pictures very much.
查清他底细
Check him out.
真是美极了
This is really beautiful.
看看这个，原本是用来装饰某个国王的宫殿的
Look at this. Used to decorate the palace of a king.
哦是啊，很漂亮
Oh, yeah. Very nice.
你怎么不说你是给柯利昂尼办事的，汤姆？
Why didn't you just say you worked for Corleone, Tom?
我以为你不过是个廉价的小骗子
I thought you were just some cheap, two-bit hustler...
约翰尼弄来诈唬我的
Johnny was running in, trying to bluff me.
我不想用他的名字，除非真的必要
I don't like to use his name unless it's really necessary.
- 你的酒怎么样，汤姆？  - 很好
- How's your drink, Tom? - Fine.
到这边来，我给你看一样真正漂亮的东西
Come with me. I want to show you something really beautiful.
你是个识货的人，对吧汤姆？
You do appreciate beauty, don't you, Tom?
就是它，60万美元的四蹄动物
There you are. $600,000 on four hooves.
我打赌俄国沙皇也从未在一匹马身上花过这么大笔钱
I'll bet Russian czars never paid that kind of dough for a single horse.
喀土穆
Khartoum.
不过我不会用他来比赛
I'm not gonna race him, though.
我要他当种马
I'm gonna put him out to stud.
- 谢谢，托尼 - 不必客气
- Thanks, Tony. - You're welcome.
- 走吧  - 我们去吃点东西
- Come on. - Let's get something to eat.
柯利昂尼先生，是约翰尼的教父
Mr. Corleone is Johnny's godfather.
对意大利人而言，这是非常虔诚、庄严、紧密的关系
To the Italian people, that's a very religious, sacred, close relationship.
这我尊重
I respect that.
告诉他 他可以跟我要求任何别的事
Just tell him he should ask me anything else.
但就这一个人情我不能给他
This is one favor I can't give him.
他被拒绝一次后 不会再要求第二次
He never asks a second favor when he's been refused the first.
- 明白吗？  - 是你不明白
- Understood? - You don't understand.
约翰尼・方廷永远拿不到那部电影
Johnny Fontane never gets that movie.
那个角色完美契合他
That part is perfect for him.
会让他成为巨星
It'll make him a big star.
我要把他赶出这一行
I'm gonna run him out of the business.
我来告诉你为什么
Let me tell you why.
约翰尼・方廷毁了一个沃茨国际最有价值的新人
Johnny Fontane ruined one of Woltz International's most valuable proteges.
五年来我们不断地训练她
For five years, we had her under training.
歌唱课、表演课、跳舞课
Singing lessons, acting lessons, dancing lessons.
我在她身上花费了成千上万的金钱
I spent hundreds of thousands of dollars on her.
我要让她成为一位巨星
I was gonna make her a big star.
我还可以更坦白些
And let me be even more frank.
让你看看我不是铁石心肠，这也不全是钱的事
Just to show you that I'm not a hard-hearted man that it's not all dollars and cents.
她人漂亮  她年轻而又单纯
She was beautiful. She was young, she was innocent!
她有着我曾拥有过最棒的屁股
She was the greatest piece of ass I've ever had
我可是占有过全世界各种美臀的人
and I've had 'em all over the world.
然后约翰尼・方廷出现了
And then Johnny Fontane comes along...
带着橄榄油的嗓音和意大利风情
with his olive oil voice and guinea charm.
然后她就跑掉了
And she runs off.
她丢下一切，令我成为笑柄
She threw it all away just to make me look ridiculous...
而我这种地位的人受不了被当作笑柄
and a man in my position can't afford to be made to look ridiculous!
现在你给我滚出去
Now you get the hell outta here!
要是那个黑手党想来硬的
And if that goombah tries any rough stuff...
你告诉他，我不是乐队领班
you tell him I ain't no bandleader.
对，我听说过那个故事
Yeah. I heard that story.
谢谢你的晚餐以及非常愉快的一晚
Thank you for the dinner and a very pleasant evening.
也许你的车能送我去机场
If your car could take me to the airport...
柯利昂尼先生是个坚持立刻听到坏消息的人
Mr. Corleone is a man who insists on hearing bad news immediately.
- 你不会太累吧，汤姆？  - 我在飞机上睡过了
- You're not too tired, are you, Tom? - No, I slept on the plane.
我这里有索洛佐的资料
I have the Sollozzo notes here.
是这样…
Now...
索洛佐，绰号“土耳其人”
Sollozzo is known as "The Turk."
他应该很善于用刀
He's supposed to be very good with a knife...
但只用在生意上，出于某种合理纠纷时
but only in matters of business with some sort of reasonable complaint.
他的生意是麻醉毒品
his business is narcotics.
他在土耳其有田地，在那里种罂粟
he has fields in Turkey where they grow the poppy...
在西西里他有工厂提炼成海洛因
and in Sicily he has the plants to process them into heroin.
现在，他需要现金
Now, he needs cash...
而且他需要来自警方的保护，为此他会分一份出来
and he needs protection from the police for which he gives a piece of the action.
我没能查出是多少
I couldn't find out how much.
塔塔利亚家族在纽约这边是他的后台
The Tattaglia family is behind him here in New York.
他们一定也有份
Now, they have to be in it for something.
桑提诺・柯利昂尼
Santino Corleone.
他的坐牢记录如何？
What about his prison record?
两次，一次在意大利，一次在这里
Two terms, one in Italy, one here.
他被认为是顶级毒枭
He's known as a top narcotics man.
桑提诺，你怎么想的？
Santino, what do you think?
白粉可以赚大钱
There's a lot of money in that white powder.
汤姆？
Tom?
我赞成，毒品比其它任何东西赚钱潜力都大
I say yes, there's more money potential in narcotics than anything else we're looking at.
就算我们不加入，别人也会
If we don't get into it, somebody else will.
也许是五大家族之一，也许他们全体
Maybe one of the five families, maybe all of them.
用他们赚到的钱，他们能买通更多警察和政治力量
With the money they earn they can buy more police and political power.
到时他们就能紧跟我们
Then they come after us.
现在我们有工会，我们有赌博
Now we have the unions, we have the gambling...
它们是最好的东西，但毒品，是未来的翘楚
and they're the best things to have, but narcotics...is a thing of the future.
如果我们不从中分一份
If we don't get a piece of that action...
我们就有失去一切的风险
we risk everything we have.
我不是指现在，而是从现在起十年之内
I mean not now, but ten years from now.
怎么样？
So?
你的回答是什么呢，爸爸？
What's your answer gonna be, Pop?
唐・柯利昂尼
Don Corleone
我需要一个有强大朋友的人
I need a man who has powerful friends.
我需要一百万元的现金
I need a million dollars in cash.
我需要你口袋里掌握的政客，唐・柯利昂尼
I need, Don Corleone, those politicians you carrying in your pocket...
就像许许多多零钱硬币
Like so many nickels and dimes.
我的家族有何利益？
What is the interest for my family?
30%
Thirty percent.
第一年你就可进帐三四百万元
In the first year, your end should be 3, 4 million dollars.
然后还会增加
And then it would go up.
塔塔利亚家族又有何利益？
And what is the interest for the Tattaglia family?
佩服
My compliments.
我来操心塔塔利亚家，从我那份里出
I'll take care of the Tattaglias outta my share.
那么，我得30%，提供财务支持…
So, I receive 30% for finance...
政治影响力和法律保护，这就是你说的
political influence and legal protection, that's what you telling me.
正是
That's right.
你为什么来找我？
Why do you come to me?
我为什么值得你这么慷慨？
Why do I deserve this generosity?
如果你把一百万现金仅仅视为“财务支持”…
If you consider a million dollars in cash...just "finance"--
我向你致敬[意大利语]  唐・柯利昂尼
我说我会见你是因为…
I said that I would see you because...
我听说你是个认真的人
I heard that you were a serious man...
应该以礼相待
to be treated with respect.
但是…
But...
我必须对你说不
I must say no to you.
而且我要告诉你我的理由
And I'll give you my reason.
没错，我有很多政界的朋友
It's true, I have a lot of friends in politics.
但他们的朋友做不了多久…
But they wouldn't be friendly very long...
一旦他们知道我的生意是毒品而非赌博的话
if they knew my business was drugs instead of gambling...
他们将之看作是无害的恶习
which they regard as a harmless vice.
- 但毒品则是肮脏的生意  - 不，唐・柯利昂尼…
- But drugs is a dirty business. - No, Don Corleone--
这对我并没有什么区别
It doesn't make any difference to me...
一个人做什么为生，你能理解的
what a man does for a living, you understand...
但你的生意就…
but your business is...
有一点危险
a little dangerous.
如果你是担心你那一百万的安全
If you're worried about security for your million...
塔塔利亚家会做担保
the Tattaglias will guarantee it.
你是说塔塔利亚家会担保我们的投资…
You're tellin' me the Tattaglias guarantee our investment--
等一下
Wait a minute.
我的弱点是对孩子们太溺爱，你看我把他们宠坏了
I have a sentimental weakness for my children and I spoil them, as you can see.
他们在应该听话时说话
They talk when they should listen.
但是，不管怎样
But, anyway
索洛佐先生，我的“不”是最终决定
Signor Sollozzo, my "no" is final...
我要恭喜你的新生意
and I wish to congratulate you on your new business.
我知道你会很成功，祝你好运
I know you'll do very well, and good luck to you...
尤其是你的生意跟我的并不冲突
especially since your interests don't conflict with mine.
谢谢
Thank you.
桑提诺
Santino
过来
Come here.
你怎么回事？
What's the matter with you?
我看你的脑子是变迟钝了
I think your brain is going soft...
自从你跟那个年轻姑娘的小喜剧上演以来
from all that comedy you're playing with that young girl.
再也不要告诉家族以外的人你在想什么了
Never tell anybody outside the family what you're thinking again.
去吧
Go on.
汤姆，这是…什么乱七八糟的
Tom, what-- What is this nonsense?
是约翰尼送的，他主演了那部新电影
It's from Johnny. He's starring in that new film.
好吧，把它拿走
Well, take it away.
把它拿那边去
Take it over there.
还有
And...
叫卢卡・布拉西来
tell Luca Brasi to come in.
我对索洛佐这人有点担心
I'm a little worried about this Sollozzo fellow.
我要你弄清楚他在耍什么把戏
I want you to find out what he's got under his fingernails, you know.
到塔塔利亚那边去
Go to the Tattaglias and...
让他们以为你与我们家族不融洽
make them think...that you're not too happy with our family...
尽量查些东西出来
and find out what you can.
我买了…我买了东西给你母亲，还有桑尼
And I got something...I got something for your mother and for Sonny...
还有一条领带给弗雷多，汤姆・黑根是雷诺兹钢笔
and a tie for Freddy...and Tom Hagen got the Reynolds pen.
- 你圣诞节想要什么？  - 我？哦，只要你
- What do you want for Christmas? - Me? Oh, just you.
醒醒[意大利语]弗雷多
叫泡利备车，我们要走了
Tell Paulie to get the car. We're going.
好的，爸
Okay, Pa.
我得自己去开车，爸，泡利今早打电话说病了
I'll have to get it myself, Pa. Paulie called in sick this morning.
泡利是个好孩子，我不介意去开车
Paulie's a good kid. I don't mind gettin' the car.
（意大利语）
卢卡
Luca.
我是布鲁诺・塔塔利亚
I am Bruno Tattaglia.
我知道
I know.
（意大利语）威士忌？战前的
...Scotch? Prewar.
我不喝酒[意大利语]
你知道我是谁吗？
You know who I am?
我认识你[意大利语]
你一直在跟塔塔利亚家族谈，对吧？[意大利语]
我认为你跟我可以做生意[意大利语]
我需要像你这么强壮的人[意大利语]
我听说你…与柯利昂尼家族不和[意大利语]
想加入我们吗？[意大利语]
我能得到什么好处[意大利语]
五万元，只是起步[意大利语]
不坏[意大利语]
同意了？[意大利语]
哦，汤姆・黑根，圣诞快乐
Ah, Tom Hagen, Merry Christmas.
我很高兴遇见你，我想跟你聊聊
I'm glad I run into you. I wanna talk to you.
我没时间
I haven't got time.
腾出点时间吧，consigliere，上车
Oh, make time, consigliere. Get in the car.
你担心什么？
What are you worried about?
我想杀你的话你早己死了
If I wanted to kill you, you'd be dead already.
上车
Get in.
等一下，弗雷多，我买点水果
Fredo, I'm gonna buy some fruit.
好的，爸
Okay, Pa.
圣诞快乐 我要买些水果
Hi. Merry Christmas.I want some fruit over there.
给我三个
Gimme three of them.
不，那个
No, that one.
弗雷多
Fredo!
爸爸
Papa.
迈克，我要是修女你会不会更喜欢我？
Mike, would you like me better if I were a nun...
就像这个故事里那样
like in the story, you know?
不会
No
那如果我是英格丽・褒曼 你会不会更喜欢我？
Then would you like me better if I were Ingrid Bergman?
这个想法不错
Now that's a thought.
迈克尔
Michael
不，如果你是英格丽・褒曼，我不会更喜欢你的
No, I would not like you better if you were Ingrid Bergman.
- 迈克尔  - 怎么回事？
- Mike-- - What's the matter?
他们没说他是死是活
They don't say if he's dead or alive.
桑尼，我是迈克尔
Sonny, Michael.
迈克尔，你到哪去了？
Michael, where you been?
他还好吗？
Is he all right?
我们还不知道，各种说法都有
We don't know yet. There's all kinds of stories.
他伤得很重，麦基
he was hit bad, Mikey.
你还在吗？
Are you there?
是的，我在
Yeah, I'm here.
你去哪儿了？我很担心
Where you been? I was worried.
汤姆没告诉你我打过电话吗？
Didn't Tom tell you I called?
没，快回家，小子
No. Look, come home, kid.
你应该在这里陪妈妈，听见没？
You should be with Mama, you hear?
好的
All right.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
桑尼
Sonny.
待在后面，快去
Stay back there. Go.
- 是谁？  - 开门，我是克里门萨
- Who is it?  - Open up. It's Clemenza.
- 什么事？  - 有更多你老子的消息
- What?  - There's more news about your old man.
街头谣传他已经死了
The word is out on the street he's already dead.
闭上你的嘴，你怎么回事？
Shut your mouth. What's the matter with you?
老天爷，桑尼，别激动，别激动
Jesus Christ! Sonny, take it easy. Take it easy.
泡利在哪？
Where was Paulie?
泡利病假了，他整个冬天都病了
Paulie was out sick. He's been sick all winter.
他病了几次？
How many times he been sick?
只有大概三四次
Only maybe three, four times.
- 我问过弗雷迪要不要另找个保镖  - 听着
- I mean I asked Freddy if he wants a different bodyguard. - Listen
- 他说不用  - 去带他来，帮我个忙
- He said no. - Pick him up. Do me a favor
立刻去带他来，我不管他病多重
pick him up right now. I don't care how sick he is.
只要他在喘气，我要你带他到我父亲的房子去
If he's breathin', I want you to bring him to my father's house now.
明白吗？现在
understand? Now.
好，你要我派人过来吗？
Yeah, you want me to send people here?
- 不不，只要你和他，去吧  - 好
- No, just you and him. Go ahead. - All right.
我会叫几个我们的人到家里来
I'm havin' a couple of our people come to the house.
- 你好  - 桑提诺・柯利昂尼吗？
-Hello? -Santino Corleone?
- 是我  - 我们抓了汤姆・黑根
-Yeah. -We have Tom hagen.
约三小时后，他会被释放，带回我们的提议
In about three hours, he'll be released with our proposition.
你做任何事之前，先听听他要说的话
Listen to everything he has to say before you do anything.
事情已然发生
What's done is done.
别发你那著名的臭脾气，行吗，桑尼？
And don't lose that famous temper of yours, huh, Sonny?
好，我会等
No, I'll wait.
你的老板死了
Your boss is dead.
我知道你在家族中不是负责武力的，汤姆
I know you're not in the muscle end of the family, Tom.
所以我不想要你害怕
so I don't want you to be scared.
我要你帮助柯利昂尼家族
I want you to help the Corleones...
我还要你帮我
and I want you to help me.
对，我们在他办公室外干掉了他
Yeah, we got him outside his office...
就在我们接了你大约一小时之后
just about an hour after we picked you up.
喝吧
Drink it.
所以现在全靠你为我跟桑尼达成和平了
So now it's up to you to make the peace between me and Sonny.
桑尼热心我的交易，不是吗？
Sonny was hot for my deal, wasn't he?
你也知道那么做是对的
And you knew it was the right thing to do.
桑尼会动用一切来追杀你
Sonny will come after you with everything he's got.
那会是他的第一个反应，的确
That'll be his first reaction, sure.
所以你得跟他讲讲道理
That's why you gotta talk some sense into him.
塔塔利亚家族全体都是我的后盾
The Tattaglia family is behind me with all their people.
纽约其它的家族…
The other New York families
会不惜一切防止全面战争
will go along with anything that will prevent a full-scale war.
我们面对现实吧，汤姆，恕我直言
Let's face it, Tom. I'm all due respect...
唐，愿他安息，已经松懈了
the Don, rest in peace, was slippin'.
十年前我能对付他吗？
Ten years ago, could I have gotten to him?
但现在他已经死了
Well, now he's dead.
他死了，汤姆，什么也不能让他复生
He's dead, Tom, and nothing can bring him back.
所以你得跟桑尼谈
So you gotta talk to Sonny.
你得跟两个头目谈，泰西欧，胖子克里门萨
You gotta talk to the caporegimes-- that Tessio, that fat Clemenza.
这是一门好生意，汤姆
It's good business, Tom.
我试试看
I'll try.
但即便是桑尼也没能力叫卢卡・布拉西停下
But even Sonny won't be able to call off Luca Brasi.
是啊，这个…
Yeah. Well--
让我来操心卢卡
Let me worry about Luca.
你只管跟桑尼谈
You just talk to Sonny.
还有另外两个孩子
And the other two kids.
我尽力而为
I'll do my best.
很好
Good.
现在…
Now
你可以走了
you can go.
我不喜欢暴力，汤姆
I don't like violence, Tom.
我是个生意人
I'm a businessman.
流血是一种大代价
Blood is a big expense.
他还活着
He's still alive.
他们打了他五枪，可他还活着
They hit him with five shots, and he's still alive!
这是我运气坏
Well, that's bad luck for me...
也是你运气坏，如果你达不成协议的话
and bad luck for you if you don't make that deal.
麦克
Mike.
你母亲在医院陪你父亲
Your mother's over in the hospital with your father.
看样子他能度过难关，谢天谢地
Looks like he's gonna pull through, thank God.
- 有好多人要对付  - 你认为如何？
- That's a lot of bad blood. - What do you think?
- 索洛佐，菲利普・塔塔利亚，布鲁诺・塔塔利亚  - 太过了，我觉得太过私怨
- Sollozzo, Philip Tattaglia, Bruno Tattaglia, Ramon... - It's too far. I think it's too personal.
唐就会仔细考虑
The Don will consider this over.
- 你要杀了他们全部？  - 喂，别插手，麦基，拜托
- You gonna kill all those guys? - Hey, stay out of it, Mikey, do me a favor
索洛佐是关键，你除掉他，一切就顺了
Stay out of it, Mickey.-Sollozzo's the key. You get rid of him, everything falls into line.
卢卡呢？索洛佐好像不太担心卢卡
What about Luca? Sollozzo didn't seem worried about Luca.
不知道，如果卢卡出卖我们，我们就有大麻烦了
I don't know. If Luca sold out, we're in a lot of trouble.
相信我，大麻烦
Believe me, a lot of trouble.
有人能跟卢卡联系上吗？
Has anyone been able to get in touch with Luca?
我们试了一整夜，他也许在外留宿
We've been tryin' all night. He might be shacked up.
- 麦基，帮我个忙，打电话给卢卡  - 卢卡从不留宿，他总是办完事回家
-Hey, Mickey, do me a favor, try him again. -Luca never sleeps over with a broad.He always goes home when he's through.
汤姆，你是Consigliere
Well, Tom, you're consigliere.
要是老头子死了我们该怎么办？大吉大利
What do we do if the old man dies, God forbid?
要是我们失去老头子
If we lose the old man...
我们就会失去政界的联系以及一半的力量
we lose our political contacts and half our strength.
纽约其它的家族可能会联合支持索洛佐
The other New York families might wind up supporting Sollozzo...
为了避免长期破坏性战争
just to avoid a long destructive war.
这都快1946年了
This is almost 1946.
没有人想再流血了
Nobody wants bloodshed anymore.
如果你父亲死了
If your father dies...
你得达成协议，桑尼
you'll make the deal, Sonny.
你说来容易，汤姆，他不是你父亲
You know, that's easy for you to say, Tom. He's not your father.
对他来说，我跟你和麦克一样是儿子
I was as much a son to him as you or Mike.
什么事？
What is it?
喂，泡利，我记得跟你说过在外面守着
Hey, Paulie, I thought I told you to stay put.
守大门的人说，他们收到一个包裹
The guy at the gates, they say they got a package.
是吗？泰西欧，去看看是什么
Yeah? Tessio, go see what it is.
- 你要我待在附近？ - 对，待在附近
- You want me to hang around? - Yeah, hang around.
- 你还好吧？ - 是的，我挺好
- You all right? - Yeah, I'm fine.
是吗？冰箱里有吃的，你饿不饿？
Yeah? There's some food in the icebox. You hungry anything?
- 不，没事，谢谢  - 喝杯酒如何？
-No, it's all right. Thanks. - How 'bout a drink?
- 一小杯白兰地能让你舒服点  - 好的，当然
a cup of little brandy? That's good to sweat it out. - All right, sure.
- 去吧，孩子  - 那或许是个好主意  - 对，没错
- Go ahead. - That might be a good idea. - Yeah, right.
我要你马上处置那个狗娘养的
I want you to take care of that son of a bitch right away.
泡利出卖了老头子  那个混蛋[意大利语]
Paulie sold out the old man.
我不想再见到他
I don't wanna see him again.
把它当作你第一件待办事项，明白吗？
Make that first thing on your list, understand?
明白
Understood.
麦基，明天，你带几个人…
Hey, Mickey, tomorrow you get a couple of guys.
到卢卡的公寓去，四处转转，等他出现
Go to Luca's apartment. Hang around, wait for him to show up.
也许我们不该让迈克尔太直接涉入
Maybe we shouldn't get Mike mixed up in this too directly.
对
Yeah.
听着…
Listen...
待在家里守电话，那就是很大帮助了
hang around the house on the phone. It'll be a big help.
再试着打给卢卡，打吧
Try Luca again. Go ahead.
- 这是什么鬼？  - 那是西西里人的口信
- What the hell is this? - It's a Sicilian message.
那表示卢卡・布拉西与鱼同眠了
It means Luca Brasi sleeps with the fishes.
- 我现在要走了  - 你今晚几点会回家？
- I'm goin' now. - What time you gonna be home tonight?
我不知道，也许会很晚
I don't know. Probably late.
- 别忘了坎诺里煎饼卷  - 好好好
- Don't forget the cannoli. - Yeah, yeah.
洛可，坐到另一边去
Rocco, sit on the other side.
你挡住后视镜了
You block the rearview mirror.
桑尼发狂了
Sonny's runnin' wild.
他已经在考虑睡床垫了
He's thinkin' of goin' to the mattresses already.
我们得在西区找个据点
We gotta find a spot over on the West Side.
你试试西43街309号
We'll try 309 West 43rd Street.
你知道西区有什么好地方吗？
You know any good spots on the West Side?
嗯，我想一下
Yeah, I'll think about it.
你开车的时候想好吗？
Well, think about it while you're drivin', will you?
我还想这个月里到纽约去呢
I wanna hit New York sometime this month.
倒车出去时留意小孩子
And watch out for the kids when you're backin' out.
泡利，我要你到39街科洛桑托店里
Paulie, I want you to go down 39th Street. Colosanto's.
去买18个床垫给大伙儿睡
Pick up 18 mattresses for the guys to sleep.
然后把账单拿给我
I want you to bring me the bill.
- 好的，那一定…  - 不，要确保是干净的
- Yeah, all right, there must be... - No, make sure they're clean.
因为那些伙计们要在那里待很长时间，你知道
because Those guys are gonna be stuck up in there for a long time, you know.
它们是干净的，他们告诉我消过毒的
They're clean. They told me they exterminate them.
消毒？用那个字很不好
"Exterminate"? That's a bad word to use.
消毒，听听这个家伙
Exterminate. Get this guy.
看看我们怎么来消灭你
See how we don't exterminate you.
- 真是好笑  - 泡利…
- Youse funny, or what? - Hey, Paulie?...
喂，靠边停车好吗？我要放水
Hey, pull over, will you? I gotta take a leak.
留下枪
Leave the gun.
拿上坎诺里煎饼卷
Take the cannoli.
喂，麦克…喂，麦基…
Hey, Mike! Hey, Mickey!
在
Yeah?
有电话找你
You're wanted on the telephone.
- 是谁？  - 是个女孩
- Who is it? - It's some girl.
- 你好，凯伊  - 你父亲还好吗？
Hello, Kay?how's your father?
他很好，他能挺过来
He's good. He's gonna make it.
我爱你
I love you.
- 迈克尔？  - 是，我知道
- Michael? - Yeah, I know.
告诉我你爱我
Tell me you love me.
我不能说
I can't talk.
你不能说吗？
Can't you say it?
我们今晚见
Yeah, I'll see you tonight.
喂，麦基，你干嘛不告诉那好姑娘你爱她？
Hey, Mickey, why don't you tell that nice girl you love her?
我全心全意爱你
I love you with all o' my heart!
要是我不能快点再见到你，我会死的
If I don't see you again a-soon, I'm-a gonna die!
过来，孩子，学点东西
Come over here, kid. Learn somethin'.
你永远不知道，有一天你也许得给20个男人做饭
You never know, you might have to cook for 20 guys someday.
看着，你开始先倒点油，然后炸大蒜
You see? You start out with a little bit of oil. Then you fry some garlic.
然后扔进几个西红柿，番茄酱
Then you throw in some tomatoes, some tomato paste.
你得炒一下，让它别粘锅
You fry it. You make sure it doesn't stick.
煮开了之后，加入香肠及肉丸
When you got it to a boil, you shove in all your sausage and meatballs.
再加一点点酒
And a little bit of wine.
以及…一点点糖
And a little bit of sugar.
那是我的秘方
And that's my trick.
你别说废话了
Why don't you cut the crap?
我有更重要的事要让你去做
I got more important things for you to do.
泡利怎么样？
How's Paulie?
哦，泡利，你再也见不到他了
Oh Paulie, won't see him no more.
你要去哪里？
Where you going?
到城里去
To the city.
派几个保镖跟他一起去
Send some bodyguards with him.
- 噢，我只是去医院看爸爸  - 我不管
- I'm just going to see Pop. - Never mind.
派人跟他一起去
Send somebody with him.
他不会有事的 索洛佐知道他是"平民"
He'll be all right. Sollozzo knows he's a civilian.
- 好吧，小心点  - 是，长官
- All right. Be careful, huh? - Yes, sir.
还是派人跟着他
Send somebody with him anyway.
我得走了
I have to go.
我能跟你一起去吗？
Can I go with you?
不行，凯伊，那里会有探员
No, Kay. There's gonna be detectives there.
媒体的人
People from the press.
我搭出租车去
I'll ride in a cab.
我不想要你卷进来
I don't want you to get involved.
我何时能再见你？
When will I see you again?
回新罕布什尔去
Go back to New Hampshire...
我打电话去你父母家找你
and I'll call you at your parents' house.
我何时才能再见你，迈克尔？
When will I see you again, Michael?
我不知道
I don't know.
你在这里干什么？
What are you doing here?
这时候你不该来
You're not supposed to be here now.
我是迈克尔・柯利昂尼
I'm Michael Corleone.
这是我父亲
This is my father.
这里没人，守卫人员都怎么了？
There's nobody here. What happened to the guards?
你父亲访客太多，他们妨碍了医院的作业
Your father just had too many visitors. They interfered with hospital service.
警察大概10分钟前要他们离开了
The police made them leave about ten minutes ago.
请给我接长滩45620
Get me Long Beach 4-5-6-2-0, please.
护士，等一下，待会儿
Nurse, wait a minute. Stay here.
- 桑尼，是迈克尔，我在医院  - 哦
- Sonny, Michael. I'm at the hospital. - Yes
听着，我来晚了，这里没有人
Listen. I got here late. There's nobody here.
什么？没人？
What? Nobody?
没人，泰西欧的人不在，没有探员，没有人
Nobody. No Tessio's men, no detectives, nobody.
就爸爸一个人
Pop is all alone.
别惊慌，我们会派人去
Don't panic. We'll send somebody.
我不会惊慌
I won't panic.
我很抱歉，但你必须离开了
I'm sorry, but you will have to leave.
你和我要把我父亲移到另一个房间
You and I are gonna move my father to another room.
现在你是否卸下这些管子，这样我们能把病床挪出去
Can you disconnect those tubes so we can move the bed out?
那绝对不行
That's out of the question.
你认识我父亲吗？
Do you know my father?
有人正要来杀他
Men are coming here to kill him.
你懂吗？
You understand?
现在请你帮我忙
Now, help me, please.
你是谁？
Who are you?
我是恩佐，那个糕饼师
I am Enzo-- the baker.
- 你还记得我吧？  - 恩佐
- You remember me? - Enzo?
是的，恩佐
Yes, Enzo.
你最好离开这里，恩佐，这里会有麻烦
You better get out of here, Enzo. There's gonna be trouble.
要是有麻烦，我留在这帮你
If there is trouble, I stay here to help you--
为了你父亲 为了你父亲
For your father. For your father.
好吧，听我说
All right, listen.
到外面等我，医院前面，好吗？
Wait for me outside, in front of the hospital. All right?
我马上出来，快去
I'll be out in a minute. Go ahead.
好的
Okay.
好好休息吧，爸
Just lie here, Pop.
现在我来照顾你
I'll take care of you now.
现在我跟你一起了
I'm with you now.
我跟你一起
I'm with you.
扔掉这个
Get rid of these.
过来
Come here.
把手放在口袋里就像你有把枪
Put your hand in your pocket like you have a gun.
你不会有事的
You'll be all right.
你没事的
You'll be okay.
你做的很好
You did good.
我以为把你们这帮意大利打手都关起来了
I thought I got all you guinea hoods locked up.
你在这里搞什么鬼？
What the hell are you doing here?
守卫我父亲的人都怎么了，警监？
What happened to the men who were guarding my father, Captain?
怎么，你这小混蛋，你算老几敢管我的事？
Why, you little punk. Who the hell are you telling me my business?
我把那些人赶走了
I pulled them guys off of here.
你马上走开，离开这医院
Now you get out of here and stay away from this hospital.
我不会走，除非你派守卫到我父亲房间去
I'm not moving until you put some guards around my father's room.
菲尔，把他带回去
Phil, take him in.
这孩子是清白的，警监
The kid's clean, Captain.
- 他是个战斗英雄，从未和…  -  该死的，我说了带他回去
- He's a war hero. He's never been busted-- - Goddamn it, I said take him in.
“土耳其人”付你多少钱陷害我父亲，警监？
What's the Turk paying you to set up my father, Captain?
抓牢他，让他站着
Take ahold of him. Stand him up.
让他站稳了
Stand him up straight.
我是柯利昂尼家的律师
I'm the attorney for the Corleone family.
这些人是私家侦探，雇来保护维多・柯利昂尼的
These men are private detectives hired to protect Vito Corleone.
他们持照携带火器
They're licensed to carry firearms.
如果你干涉，明早你得面对一位法官并说明理由
If you interfere, you'll have to appear before a judge in the morning and show cause.
好了，让他走
All right, let him go.
来吧
Come on.
这些新面孔是怎么回事？
What's with all the new faces?
现在会需要他们的
Gonna need 'em now.
经过医院的事之后，桑尼气疯了
After the hospital thing, Sonny got mad.
我们今早四点干掉了布鲁诺・塔塔利亚
We hit Bruno Tattaglia at 4:00 this morning.
老天爷
Jesus Christ.
这里看起来像是座要塞
Looks like a fortress around here.
（意大利语）
100个雇佣枪手在街头，一天24小时
A hundred button men on the street, 24 hours a day.
那土耳其人敢露出一根毛就死定了，相信我
That Turk shows one hair on his ass, he's dead. Believe me.
迈克尔，过来，让我看看你
Hey, Michael, come here. Let me look at you.
你样子好看，挺好看，漂亮极了
You look beautiful. Just beautiful. You're gorgeous.
喂，听听这个
Hey, listen to this.
那“土耳其人”，他想谈判
The Turk, he wants to talk.
想想那个狗娘养的有多紧张
Imagine the nerve on this son of a bitch.
昨晚跟我们赌一把，今天他想面谈
Craps out last night, now he wants a meeting today.
- 他怎么说？  - 他怎么说？
- What'd he say? - What did he say?
他要我们派迈克尔去听取提议
He wants us to send Michael to hear the proposition.
并保证 那条件好到我们不会拒绝
And the promise is that the deal is so good that we can't refuse.
那布鲁诺・塔塔利亚呢？
What about Bruno Tattaglia?
那是条件的一部分
That's part of the deal.
布鲁诺抵消了他们对我父亲所做的
Bruno cancels out what they did to my father.
桑尼，我们得听听他们怎么说
Sonny, we ought to hear what they have to say.
不不，不要了，这次不要，Consigliere
No more. Not this time, Consigliere.
不再和谈，不再讨论，不再上索洛佐的当
No more meetings, no discussions, no more Sollozzo tricks.
你给他们一个信息：我要索洛佐
You give them one message-- I want Sollozzo.
否则就是全面开战，我们去睡床垫
If not, it's all-out war. We go to the mattresses.
桑尼，其它家族不会支持的
Sonny, the other families won't sit still for a war.
- 那就叫他们把索洛佐交给我  - 桑尼，你父亲不爱听这话
- Then they hand me Sollozzo. - Your father wouldn't hear this.
这是生意，不是个人恩怨
This is business, not personal.
他们枪击我父亲…
They shot my father.
即便枪击你父亲也是生意，不是私事，桑尼
Even shooting your father was business, not personal, Sonny.
那么生意就不得不受损了，行吗？
Well, then business will have to suffer. All right?
听着，帮我个忙，汤姆
And listen, do me a favor, Tom--
别再建议如何修修补补
No more advice on how to patch things up.
只要帮我赢，好吗？
Just help me win, please. All right?
我查了这个麦克劳斯基警监，他打断麦克的下巴
I found out about this Captain McCluskey who broke Mike's jaw.
他怎么样？
What about him?
他绝对在索洛佐的工资名单上，而且拿钱很多
He's definitely on Sollozzo's payroll, and for big money.
麦克劳斯基同意当索洛佐的保镖
McCluskey has agreed to be the Turk's bodyguard.
你必须要了解，桑尼
What you have to understand, Sonny...
当索洛佐有了这样的警卫，他就无懈可击了
is that while Sollozzo's being guarded like this,  he is invulnerable.
从来没人射杀过纽约警官，从未
Nobody has ever gunned down a New York police captain. Never.
那会是个大灾难
It would be disastrous.
五大家族全都会追杀你，桑尼
All the five families would come after you, Sonny.
柯利昂尼家族会被驱逐
The Corleone family would be outcast.
即便是老头的政治保护都会找掩护躲起来
Even the old man's political protection would run for cover.
所以我拜托你
So do me a favor.
好好考虑这一点
Take this into consideration.
好吧  我们等
All right, we'll wait.
我们不能等
We can't wait.
Can't wait.
我不管索洛佐说什么条件，他会杀了爸爸，就这样
I don't care what Sollozzo says about a deal. He's gonna kill Pop. That's it.
那是他的关键
That's the key for him.
我们必须干掉索洛佐
We've got to get Sollozzo.
麦克说得对
Mike is right.
我来问问你
Let me ask you something first.
这个麦克劳斯基呢？
What about this McCluskey?
我们拿这个条子怎么办？
What do we do with this cop here?
他们想跟我会面，对吧？
They want to have a meeting with me, right?
那会是我、麦克劳斯基及索洛佐
It will be me...McCluskey and Sollozzo.
我们来安排会面
Let's set the meeting.
找我们的线人打听出在哪里举行
Get our informers to find out where it's going to be held.
我们坚持要公共场所，一间酒吧，一家餐厅
We insist it's a public place-- a bar, a restaurant.
某个人多的地方，这样我感觉安全
Someplace where there's people, so I feel safe.
我跟他们一见面，他们就会搜我身，对吧？
They're gonna search me when I first meet them, right?
所以我身上不能有武器
So I can't have a weapon on me then.
但如果克里门萨能想出一个办法
But if Clemenza can figure a way...
替我在那里布置下武器
to have a weapon planted there for me...
那我就能杀了他们两个
then I'll kill them both.
你要怎么做？乖乖的大学生
What are you gonna do? Nice college boy, huh?
以前不想跟家族事务混在一起
Didn't want to get mixed up in the family business.
现在你想干掉一个警监？
Now you want to gun down a police captain?
为什么？因为他小小扇了你一耳光？
Why? 'Cause he slapped you in the face a little bit?
你以为这是什么？军队吗？
What're you think? This is the army?
在一哩以外开枪打他们？
where you shoot them a mile away?
你必须离这么近，然后“砰”
You gotta get up close, like this and--
你漂亮的常春藤名校服上溅满他们的脑浆
You blow their brains all over your nice Ivy League suit.
- 过来  - 桑尼
- Come here.  - Sonny.
你把这事当成私仇了
You're taking this very personal.
汤姆，这是生意，而这位把它当私仇了
Tom, this is business, and this man is taking it very, very personal.
不能杀条子是哪里来的说法？
Where does it say you can't kill a cop?
- 好了，麦基  - 汤姆，等一下
- Come on, Mikey. - Tom, wait a minute.
我说的这个条子，他跟毒品搅在一起
I'm talking about a cop that's mixed up in drugs.
我说的是个不诚实的条子，不正当的条子
I'm talking about a dishonest cop, a crooked cop...
跟犯罪集团混在一起，终于遭了报应
who got mixed up in the rackets and got what was coming to him.
这是个精彩的故事
That's a terrific story.
我们的工资单上有报社的人，对吧汤姆？
We have newspaper people on the payroll, don't we, Tom?
他们也许会喜欢这种故事
They might like a story like that.
他们也许会，只是也许
They might. They just might.
这不是私仇，桑尼，纯粹是公事
It's not personal, Sonny. It's strictly business.
它从没用过
It's as cold as they come.
不可能追踪，所以不用担心指纹，麦克
Impossible to trace, so you don't worry about prints, Mike.
我贴了特殊胶布在扳机和柄上
I put a special tape on the trigger and the butt.
来，试试
Here. Try it.
怎么？扳机太紧了？
What's the matter, the trigger too tight?
- 哇，我的耳朵  - 对，我没处理枪声
- My ears. - Yeah, I left it noisy.
这样就可以吓走多管闲事的旁观者
That way it scares any pain-in-the-ass innocent bystanders away.
好了，你杀了他俩，现在你做什么？
All right, you shot them both. Now what do you do?
坐下，吃完我的晚餐
Sit down, finish my dinner.
好了，小子，别捣乱啦
Come on, kid. Don't fool around.
就让你的手顺身侧垂下，让枪滑走
Just let your hand drop to your side and let the gun slip out.
人人都会认为你还拿着它
Everybody will still think you got it.
他们会盯着你的脸，麦克
They're gonna be staring at your face, Mike...
所以快步离开那地方，但不要跑
so walk out of the place real fast, but you don't run.
别直视任何人，但你也不要挪开目光
Don't look nobody directly in the eye, but don't look away, either.
他们会被你吓坏，相信我，所以什么也不用担心
They're gonna be scared stiff of you, believe me...so don't worry about nothing.
你看，你会全身而退的
You know, you're gonna turn out all right.
你休个长假，去谁也不知道的地方
You take a long vacation, nobody knows where...
而我们来收拾善后
and we're gonna catch the hell.
你觉得情况会有多糟？
How bad do you think it's gonna be?
相当他妈的糟糕
Pretty goddamn bad.
可能其它所有家族会联合对付我们
Probably all the other families will line up against us.
那也没关系
That's all right.
这种事大概每隔5年会发生，或10年
These things gotta happen every five years or so. Ten years.
有助于消除不和
Helps to get rid of the bad blood.
从上次以来已有10年了
Been ten years since the last one.
你看你得一开始就制止他们
You know you gotta stop them at the beginning...
就像他们本该在慕尼黑制止希特勒
like they should have stopped Hitler at Munich.
他们那次就不该让他逃过去，那是自找麻烦
They should have never let him get away with that. They was just asking for big trouble.
知道吗，麦克
You know, Mike,
我们都以你为荣…当战斗英雄什么的
we was all proud of you... being a hero and all.
你父亲也是
Your father too.
没有，一点线索没有，什么也没有
Nothing. Not a hint. Absolutely nothing.
连索洛佐的人也不知道在会面哪里举行
Even Sollozzo's people don't know where the meeting will be held.
我们有多少时间？
How much time do we have?
一个半小时以后，他们在杰克丹普西餐厅前接你上车
pick you up in front of Jack Dempsey's in an hour and a half--
正好一个半小时以后
exactly an hour and a half.
我们可以派盯梢，看看最后去哪儿
We could put a tail on them, see how it turns out.
索洛佐会在街上乱转 甩掉我们的人
Sollozzo'll lose our ass going around the block.
谈判中间人呢？
What about the negotiator?
他在我那里和我的手下玩皮纳克纸牌
He's over at my place playing pinochle with a couple of my men.
他很高兴  我们在让他赢
He's happy. They're letting him win.
这对麦克太冒险了
It's too much of a risk for Mike.
也许我们该取消，桑尼
Maybe we ought to call it off, Sonny.
那个中间人要一直玩牌等到麦克安然无恙回来才走
The negotiator keeps on playing cards until Mike's back safe and sound.
那他干嘛不直接对车里不管什么人开火呢？
So why doesn't he just blast who's ever in the goddamn car?
太危险了，他们会注意的
Too dangerous. They'll be looking for that.
索洛佐也许根本就不在车上，桑尼
Sollozzo might not even be in the car, Sonny.
我来接
I got it.
布朗克斯的路易斯餐厅
Louis Restaurant in the Bronx.
可靠吗？
Well, is it reliable?
麦克劳斯基的分局里有我的人
That's my man in McCluskey's precinct.
警监必须一天24小时待命
A police captain's got to be on call 24 hours a day.
他八点到十点会去那里
He signed out at that number between 8:00 and 10:00.
有谁知道那个地方？
Anybody know this joint?
当然，我知道
Yeah, sure. I do.
对我们太理想了
It's perfect for us.
小型家庭餐厅，食物不错
A small family place, good food.
大家各吃各的，太理想了
Everyone minds his business. It's perfect.
彼得，他们那儿有个旧式马桶
Pete, they got an old-fashioned toilet--
你知道就是水箱有吊链的那种
You know, the box and the chain thing.
我们或许可把枪用胶带绑在那后面
We might be able to tape the gun behind it.
好的
All right.
麦克，你去餐厅
Mike, you go to the restaurant.
你吃着谈上一会儿，要放松
You eat, you talk for a while, you relax.
你让他们放松下来
You make them relax.
然后你站起来，去解手
Then you get up and go take a leak.
不，更好的是，你要求得到许可再去
No, better still, you ask for permission to go.
等你回来，你就开枪
And when you come back, you come out blasting.
不要心存侥幸，每人脑袋上来两枪
And don't take any chances. Two shots in the head apiece.
好了，听着，我要一个好手，真正的好手去藏枪
Now, listen. I want somebody good-- and I mean very good-- to plant that gun.
我不想我兄弟走出厕所手里只握着自己的老二，明白？
I don't want him coming out of that toilet with just his dick in his hands, all right?
枪会在那里的
The gun will be there.
好，听着，你开车送他，事后再接他回来
All right, listen. You drive him and you pick him up after the job.
来吧，赶紧行动
Come on. Let's move.
他有没有…告诉你完事就扔掉枪？
Did he tell you to drop the gun right away?
有，上百万次了
Yeah, a million times.
好了
Now
你别忘了，每人头上两枪，一出厕所后就打
You don't forget-- two shots apiece in the head as soon as you come out the door.
我们走
Let's go.
你认为要多久我才能回家？
How long do you think it'll be before I can come back?
至少得一年，麦克
At least a year, Mike.
听着，我会协调妈妈那边…
Listen, I'll square with Mom
你知道你走前不能去看她，还有…
you know you're not seeing her before you leave and...
我会给你那女友送个消息
I'll get a message to that girlfriend
等我觉得合适的时候
when I think the time is right.
保重
Take care.
- 再见，麦克  - 汤姆
- See you, Mike.  - Tom
我很高兴你来了，麦克
I'm glad you came, Mike.
我希望我们能摆平所有事情
I hope we can straighten everything out.
我说这太可怕了，这完全不是我想要的发展
I mean this is terrible. It's not the way I wanted things to go at all.
完全就不该发生的
It should have never happened.
我想在今晚摆平所有事
I want to straighten everything out tonight.
我不想要我父亲再受打扰
I don't want my father bothered anymore.
他不会了，麦克
He won't be, Mike.
我以我的孩子发誓不会
I swear on my children he won't.
但我们谈的时候你得心态开放
But you got to keep an open mind when we talk.
我是说，我希望你不像你哥哥那样热血
I mean I hope you're not a hothead like your brother Sonny.
你没办法跟他谈正事
You can't talk business with him.
(意大利语)
呃，他是个好孩子
He's a good kid.
那晚的事我很抱歉，麦克
I'm sorry about the other night, Mike.
我得搜你身，转过来
I gotta frisk you, so turn around, huh?
跪在椅子上，面向我
On your knees, facing me.
我想我干这行已经嫌老了
I guess I'm getting too old for my job.
太厌烦
Too grouchy.
受不了别人的激怒
Can't stand the aggravation.
你知道是怎么回事
You know how it is.
他没武器
He's clean.
我们要去新泽西？
We're going to New Jersey?
也许
Maybe.
干得好，卢
Nice work, Lou.
这餐厅的意大利菜怎么样？
How's the Italian food in this restaurant?
不错
Good.
试试小牛肉，是城里最棒的
Try the veal. It's the best in the city.
我就点它了
I'll have it.
快[意大利语]
好了[意大利语]
我要跟麦克说意大利语
I'm gonna speak Italian to Mike.
请便
Go ahead.
- 我很抱歉  - 算了
要知道，你父亲身上发生的事，是生意
我很尊重你的父亲
但你父亲的想法过时了
你必须理解 我为什么做出那种事
我理解这种事
- 真的理解  - 是吗？
现在我们不得不考虑
你们跟塔塔利亚家族之间的事
我们必须想出办法 何去何从
（这里几句我没法翻译，没英语字幕了）
（这几句是我猜着翻译的）
我所关心的是…
什么？
怎么说来着？
我想要的…
What I want...
对我来说最重要的…
what's most important to me--
就是我要得到一项保证
is that I have a guarantee:
不会再有对我父亲生命的威胁
No more attempts on my father's life.
我能给你什么保证，麦克？
What guarantees could I give you, Mike?
我是被追杀的那个
I am the hunted one.
我错过了我的机会
I missed my chance.
你太看得起我了，孩子
You think too much of me, kid.
我没有那么聪明
I'm not that clever.
我想要的只是停战而已
All I want is a truce.
我得去洗手间
I have to go to the bathroom.
可以吗？
Is that all right?
想去就去吧
You gotta go, you gotta go.
我搜过了，他没武器
I frisked him. He's clean.
别去太久
Don't take too long.
我搜过好几千小混混了
I've frisked a thousand young punks.
(意大利语)
(警方追捕警察杀手)
(城市镇压有组织犯罪)
(警监与毒贩勾结)
(黑帮人物巴茨尼因黑社会冲突接受询问)
(黑帮世界暴力三月)
(辛迪加大亨维多・柯利昂尼返家)
喂，转进来
Hey, come on.
好了，你接手
Okay, you take over.
我爱你，爷爷
I love you, Grandpa.
- 对不起，爸，他还不认识你  - 没事
I'm sorry, Pa. He doesn't know you yet. - It's all right.
来吧，大个子，念给爷爷听
Here you are, big guy. Give it to Grandpa.
好
Okay.
“我祝你早日康复，爷爷，我希望能快点见到你
"I hope you get well, Grandpa... and I wish I would see you soon.
“爱你的孙子  法兰克”
Love, your grandson, Frank."
跟你妈妈走吧
Go with your mother.
- 去吧，把他们带到楼下  - 来，快来
- Go ahead. Take 'em downstairs. - Come on.
来吧
Come on.
走吧，卡洛，你也是
Go on, Carlo. You too.
走吧
Go on.
你要烤鸡？那是他最喜欢的
I got chicken cacciatore for you, sweetheart.
我知道  但你能吃多少呢？
But how much can you eat?
你怎么了，卡洛？
What's the matter with you, Carlo?
闭嘴，去摆桌子
Shut up and set the table.
自从麦克劳斯基被杀后
Since McCluskey's killing...
警方瓦解了我们多数业务
the police have been cracking down on most of our operations.
其它的家族也一样
And also the other families'.
有很多冲突
Been a lot of bad blood.
他们打击我们，所以…
They hit us, so...
我们反击他们
we hit them back.
透过我们报社中的联系，我们放了很多材料
Through our contacts in the newspapers... we've been able to put out a lot of material...
麦克劳斯基在毒品交易上与索洛佐的勾结
about McCluskey being linked with Sollozzo in the drug rackets.
所以事情已经开始放松了
See, things are starting to loosen up.
爸爸，我…派弗雷多去拉斯维加斯
Dad, I'm sending Fredo to Las Vegas...
在洛杉矶的唐・弗朗西斯科的保护之下
under the protection of Don Francesco of L.A.
我要他休息一下
I want him to rest.
- 我要学习赌场生意  - 对
- I'm going to learn the casino business. - Yeah.
迈克尔在哪里？
Where is Michael?
是迈克尔杀了索洛佐
It was Michael who killed Sollozzo.
不过他很安全
But he's safe.
我们会把他弄回来的
We're starting to work to bring him back now.
我要你查出那个小皮条客塔塔利亚藏在哪里
I want you to find out where that little pimp Tattaglia is hiding.
我要他的命，现在
I want his ass now-- right now.
- 喂，桑尼  - 什么？
- Hey, Sonny. - What?
事情刚开始缓和下来一点
Things are starting to loosen up a little bit.
如果你去追塔塔利亚，一切又会失控
If you go after Tattaglia, all hell's going to break loose.
让硝烟平静，爸爸能去谈判
Let the smoke clear. Pop can negotiate.
不，爸爸在好转之前什么都不能做
No, Pop can't do nothing till he's better.
我要决定什么对我们最有利
I'm gonna decide what's gonna be--
好的，但你开仗耗费了我们一大笔钱
All right, but your war's costing us a lot of money.
没有任何进帐，我们不能做生意
Nothing's coming in. We can't do business.
他们也不行，别担心，拜托你别担心
Neither can they. Don't worry about it.
- 我们耗不起  - 不会再有消耗战了
- We can't afford a stalemate. - Well there ain't no more stalemate
我会宰了那老混蛋来做结束，我要…
I'm gonna end it by killing that old bastard. I'm gonna...
对，你名声在外了，我希望你能高兴
Yeah, you're getting a great reputation. I hope you're enjoying it.
你照我叫你做的去做就好了
You just do what I tell you to do!
该死的，如果我有个战时Consigliere，一个西西里人
Goddamn it, if I had a wartime consigliere-- a Sicilian--
我就不会是这个样子
I wouldn't be in this shape!
爸爸有坚科，看看我有什么？
Pop had Genco. Look what I got.
对不起，我不是有意的
I'm sorry. I didn't mean that.
妈妈做了点晚餐，今天是星期天
Mom made a little dinner. It's Sunday.
你看，黑鬼正过着好日子呢…
You know, niggers are having a good time with...
在我们哈林区的赌场
with our policy banks up there in Harlem.
开着新凯迪拉克，一注押50%
Driving them new Cadillacs, paying 50% on a bet.
我早知会这样，只要他们开始挣大钱
I knew that was gonna happen as soon as they started making big money.
爸爸从不在餐桌上当着孩子们谈生意
Papa never talked business at the table in front of the kids.
- 闭嘴，康妮…  - 不准你叫她闭嘴
-Shut up, Connie. -Don't you ever tell her to shut up.
- 你听明白了吗？  - 桑提诺
-You got that? -Santino
不要干预
don't interfere.
你看，桑尼、汤姆，我想跟你们谈谈，也许晚饭后？
Look, Sonny, Tom, I'd like to talk to you, maybe after dinner.
我可以为家族做更多…
I could be doing more for the family.
我们不在餐桌上谈公事
We don't discuss business at the table.
吻你的手，唐・汤玛西诺
麦基
你怎么离开房子那么远？
你知道我得对你父亲负责你的性命
保镖们都在这里
还是很危险
我听纽约的桑提诺说的
你的敌人知道你在这里了
桑提诺有没有说 我何时能回去？
还不行
这事情根本谈不上
谢谢
你现在要去哪里?
柯利昂尼村
坐我的车去
我想走路
小心点
迈克尔，柯利昂尼村到了
男人全都到哪儿去了？
他们全都死于血仇
看，这里是死者的姓名
妈妈咪呀，好一个美女
我看你是被那道霹雳击中了
迈克尔
在西西里，女人比lupara[猎枪]还危险
打猎有收获吗？
你认识这一带所有的女孩吗?
我们看到几个真正的美人
其中一个让我们的朋友被霹雳击中了
她会诱出他心中的恶魔
对啊，真的是应有尽有
是吧，卡洛？
应有尽有
那样的头发、嘴巴
嘴巴
这一带的女孩很漂亮，但是贞洁正派
这个穿着紫色衣服
头发上绑着紫色的缎带
看起来像希腊人而不是意大利人
像希腊人，不像意大利人
- 你认识她吗？  - 你认识她吗？
不
这个镇子里没有那样的女孩
我的天  我明白了
有什么不对了？
我们走
是他女儿
叫他出来
不不不，叫他出来
法布里吉奥，你翻译
是的，先生
如果我冒犯了你，我道歉
I apologize if I offended you.
我在这个国家是个外来人
I'm a stranger in this country...
我无意冒犯你和你女儿
and I meant no disrespect to you or your daughter.
我是个美国人，躲在西西里
I'm an American hiding in Sicily.
我的名字是迈克尔・柯利昂尼
My name is Michael Corleone.
有人愿意出高价获知这个消息
There are people who would pay a lot of money for that information.
但那样你女儿会失去父亲
But then your daughter would lose a father...
而不是得到一位丈夫
instead of gaining a husband.
我想跟你女儿见面
I want to meet your daughter...
在你的准许之下
with your permission...
以及你家人的监督之下
and under the supervision of your family...
满怀诚意
with all respect.
星期天早上到我家来
我叫维泰利
谢谢
她叫什么名字？
阿波罗妮娅
很美
这是我女儿，阿波罗妮娅
这位是迈克尔・柯利昂尼先生
谢谢
不客气
你的眼睛怎么了？
不不，没什么，没事
嘿，我要搞到你晕
Hey, I'll knock you dizzy.
废话少说
Save it for the library.
来吧，我们得去接我妹妹，咱们走
Come on, we gotta pick up my sister. Lets' go.
怎么了？
What's the matter?
是我的错
It was my fault!
- 他在哪？  - 桑尼，求你了
- Where is he?  - Sonny, please.
是我的错，桑尼，是我的错，我打了他
It was my fault. Sonny, it was my fault. I hit him.
我先开始打他的，求你了，桑尼
I started a fight with him. Please, Sonny.
我打了他，他才打的我，我…
I hit him, so he hit me. I...
好了
Okay.
好了，我只是叫医生来看你，好吗？
Okay, I'm just gonna get a doctor to come and take a look at you.
桑尼，求你什么也别做，求你什么也别做
Sonny, please don't do anything. Please don't do anything.
你是怎么了？我会做什么？
What's the matter with you? What am I gonna do?
我会让这孩子没出生就当孤儿吗？
Am I gonna make that baby an orphan before he's born?
好了吗？
All right?
你们这帮西班牙傻蛋还在重注押洋基队吗？
You spic slobs still betting the Yankees pretty heavy?
叫他不要再接受投注了好吗？
Tell him to stop taking action, all right?
你上周末输给我的钱够多了
You lost enough money last weekend to me.
卡洛，过来，过来！
Carlo, come here.
来啊
Come on.
你再碰我妹妹一下我就杀了你
You touch my sister again, I'll kill you.
(意大利语)
没想到你会来，凯伊
Weren't expecting you, Kay.
你应该先打个电话来
You should call.
没错，我打过
Yes, well, I have.
我是说，我试过写信和打电话
I mean I've tried writing and calling.
现在，我要和迈克尔联络
Now, I wanna reach Michael.
没人知道他在哪
Nobody knows where he is.
我们知道他没事，但仅此而已了
We know he's all right, but that's all.
那是怎么回事？
What was that?
那是一场事故，但没有人受伤
That's an accident. But nobody was hurt.
汤姆
Tom.
能不能请你 把这封信交给迈克尔？拜托了
Would you give this letter to Michael, please? Please?
如果我接受了
if I accepted that
在法庭上，它就可以证实我知道他在哪里
in a court of law they could prove I have knowledge of his whereabouts.
耐心点，凯伊，他会与你联络的，好吗？
Just be patient, Kay. He'll get in touch with you.
我让我的出租车走了，我能否进去另叫一辆？
I let my cab go. Can I come in to call another one pleas?
来吧  对不起  来吧
Come on. I'm sorry. Come on.
卡洛在吗？
Is Carlo there?
- 你是哪位？  - 我是卡洛的一个朋友
- Who's this? - This is a friend of Carlo's.
你能不能告诉他 我今晚晚些才有空？
Would you tell him that I can't make it tonight until later?
婊子
Bitch.
- 晚餐在桌上  - 我还不饿
- Dinner's on the table. - I'm not hungry yet.
- 晚餐在桌上快凉了  - 我晚点再吃
- Your food is on the table. It's getting cold. - I'll eat out later.
你刚叫我给你做晚饭的
You just told me to make you dinner.
- 喂，操你妈[意大利语]  - 我才操你妈[意大利语]
-Hey, vaffanculo, eh?  -I'll vaffanculo you!
她这嘴真脏，这意大利小妞
She has a filthy mouth, this little guinea brat.
对了，全砸烂，你这宠坏了的意大利小妞，全砸掉
That's it. Break it all, you spoiled guinea brat. Break it all!
你怎么不把那个妓女带回家吃晚饭？
Why don't you bring your whore home for dinner?
也许我会的，有何不可？
Maybe I will. Why not?
给我清干净
Now clean it up!
我才不要
Like hell I will!
清干净，你这宠坏了的意大利小妞
Clean it up, you guinea spoiled brat!
清干净，清干净，我说清干净
Clean it up! Clean it up! I said clean it up!
清干净
Clean it up!
不
No!
清干净，你这婊子养的
Clean it up! You son of a bitch!
清理掉
Clean it!
清干净
Clean it up!
好，来啊，杀我，当凶手啊，像你爸一样
Come on, now! Kill me! Be a murderer like your father!
- 来吧，你们姓柯利昂尼的全是凶手  - 我恨你
- Come on, all you Corleones are murderers! - I hate you!
- 来啊  - 我要杀了你
- Come on! - I'll kill you!
来啊，杀了我，给我滚
Kill me! Get up! Get out of here!
- 我恨你   - 好，赶紧的，我要杀你了
- I hate you! - Now, go ahead. now I'll kill you.
你这意大利小妞
You guinea brat, you.
滚出来
Get out here!
康妮，怎么回事？
Connie, what's the matter?
我听不见你说的，什么事？
I can't hear you. What is it?
康妮，说大声点，孩子在哭
Connie, talk louder. The baby's crying.
桑提诺，我听不懂，我不明白
Santino, I can't understand-- I don't know. I don't understand.
什么事，康妮？
Yeah, Connie.
听着，你在那里等着
Listen, you wait there.
不，你在那等着就好了
No, you just wait there.
那婊子养的
That son of a bitch.
婊子养的
Son of a bitch.
- 桑尼，怎么了？  - 王八蛋
- Sonny, what's the matter?
快他妈开门 站起来
Open the goddamn gate. Get off your ass.
桑尼
Sonny.
让开！
Get out!
桑尼，桑尼，下来
Sonny. Sonny, come on!
滚开
Get out of here!
跟着他，快点
Go after him. Go on.
王八蛋
Son of a bitch.
赶紧，赶紧…
Come on! Come on!
给我一口
Give me a drop.
我妻子在楼上哭
My wife is crying upstairs.
我听见车子开到家里来
I hear cars coming to the house.
我的Consigliere
Consigliere of mine...
我想你应该告诉你的唐，人人都知道的那件事了
I think you should tell your Don what everyone seems to know.
我什么也没告诉妈妈
I didn't tell Mama anything.
我刚才正要去叫醒你并告诉你
I was about to come up and wake you just now and tell you.
但你需要先喝一杯
But you needed a drink first.
是
Ya.
现在你喝过酒了
Now you've had your drink.
他们在堤道上枪击了桑尼
They shot Sonny on the causeway.
他死了
He's dead.
我不要做调查
I want no inquiries made.
我不要复仇行动
I want no acts of vengeance.
我要你安排一次会议
I want you to arrange a meeting...
与五大家族的首领
with the heads of the five families.
这场战争现在停止
This war stops now.
打电话给博纳塞拉
Call Bonasera.
我们现在需要他了
We need him now.
我是汤姆・黑根
This is Tom Hagen...
按维多・柯利昂尼的要求 打这个电话
calling for Vito Corleone, at his request.
你欠你的唐一次服务
Now, you owe your Don a service.
他毫不怀疑你会回报他
he has no doubt that you will repay it.
他在一小时后会到你的殡仪馆去
Now, he will be at your funeral parlor in one hour.
去那里迎接他
Be there to greet him.
我的朋友
Well, my friend...
你准备好为我服务了吗？
are you ready to do me this service?
是的
Yes.
你要我做什么？
What do you want me to do?
我要你用上你全部力量，全部技能
I want you to use all your powers... and all your skills.
我不要他母亲看到他这个样子
I don't want his mother to see him this way.
看看他们是怎么残害了我的孩子
Look how they massacred my boy.
教你英语安全一点
我会英语
星期一、星期二、星期三
Monday, Tuesday, Thursday...
星期四、星期五、星期日、星期六
Wednesday, Friday, Sunday, Saturday
- 哦，好极了  - 快来快来
- Bravo! - Come on, come on.
欢迎，唐・汤玛西诺
巴勒莫那边怎么样？
你好，唐・汤玛西诺
迈克尔在教我开车
来，我开给你看
巴勒莫那边怎么样？
年轻人不再尊重任何事了
时代越变越糟
这地方对你己变得太危险了
我要你搬到锡拉库萨附近的一座别墅去，马上
有什么不对了?
有坏消息，美国来的
你哥哥桑尼
他们杀了他
我们走了  你答应的
- 法布里吉奥  - 什么事？
- Fabrizio. - Yes, sir?
备车
你要自己开吗，老板？
Are you driving yourself, boss?
是的
Yes.
你妻子跟你一起去吗？
Is your wife coming with you?
不，我要你送她回娘家，等一切安全点再说
Take her to her father's house till I know things are safe.
好的，随你吩咐，老板
Anything you say, boss.
卡罗  阿波罗妮娅呢？
她想给你个惊喜，她要开车
她会当个好的美国太太
等一下  我去拿行李
法布里吉奥
你要去哪里？
迈克尔，在那边等着，我开过去
不！不，阿波罗妮娅…
唐・巴茨尼，我要谢谢你帮我组织今天这次会议
Don Barzini, I want to thank you for helping me organize this meeting here today.
还有其它五大家族的首领，纽约和新泽西的
And also the other heads of the five families... from New York and New Jersey.
布朗克斯区的卡迈恩・柯尼奥
Carmine Cuneo from the Bronx.
以及…布鲁克林的
From Brooklyn...
菲利普・塔塔利亚
Philip Tattaglia.
来自斯塔顿岛的
And from Staten Island...
维克多・斯特拉基
we have with us Victor Strachi.
以及所有其他的伙伴们，远自加州和堪萨斯城
And all the other associates that came as far... as from California and Kansas City...
以及全国其它各地区
and all the other territories of the country.
谢谢你们
Thank you.
事情怎么会搞得这么过火？
How did things ever get so far?
我不知道
I don't know.
如此的不幸，如此没有必要
It was so unfortunate and so unnecessary.
塔塔利亚失去了一个儿子
Tattaglia lost a son...
我也失去了一个儿子
and I lost a son.
我们两抵了
We're quits
如果塔塔利亚同意
and if Tattaglia agrees...
我愿意 让事情回到过去的路子上
then I'm willing to let things go on the way they were before.
我们都感谢唐・柯利昂尼 召开这次会议
We are all grateful to Don Corleone for calling this meeting.
我们都了解他是个说话算数的人
We all know him as a man of his word.
一个谦虚的人，总是能听进去道理
A modest man. He'll always listen to reason.
是的，唐・巴茨尼
Yes, Don Barzini.
他太谦虚了
He's too modest.
他有那么多法官和政客在自己口袋里
He had all the judges and politicians in his pocket.
他却拒绝分享他们
He refused to share them.
何时？我何时拒绝过通融？
When？ When did I ever refuse an accommodation?
你们在座的全都认识我
All of you know me here.
我何时曾经拒绝过？除了一次
When did I ever refuse, except one time?
那为什么呢？
And why?
因为我相信毒品生意 在往后几年会毁了我们
Because I believe this drug business...is gonna destroy us in the years to come.
我是说，它不像赌博、酒类或甚至女人
I mean, it's not like gambling or liquor or even women...
那是如今多数人想要的东西
which is something that most people want nowadays
被教会的大人物[意大利语]所禁止
and is forbidden to them by the pezzonovante of the church.
即使警察过去在赌博和其它方面一直帮我们
Even the police departments that have helped us in the past with gambling and other things
但一提到毒品 他们会拒绝帮忙
are gonna refuse to help us when it comes to narcotics.
那时候我相信是这样，现在我也相信
And I believed that then... and I believe that now.
时代已经变了
Times have changed.
不像往日那样了
It's not like the old days...
那时我们能为所欲为
when we could do anything we want.
拒绝不是为友之道
A refusal is not the act of a friend.
如果唐・柯利昂尼掌握纽约全体法官和政客
If Don Corleone had all the judges and politicians in New York...
那他就必须分享，或让我们都能利用他们
then he must share them or let others use them.
他必须让我们从这口井里打水
He must let us draw the water from the well.
当然，他可以为这样的服务开出账单
Certainly, he can present a bill for such services.
毕竟，我们不是共产党
After all, we are not Communists.
我同样不相信毒品
I also don't believe in drugs.
多年来我额外付费给我的人
For years, I paid my people extra...
让他们不去做那种生意
so they wouldn't do that kind of business.
有人来找他们，并且说：“我有白粉
Somebody comes to them and says, "I have powders.
“只要你投入3、4千资金
If you put up a three, four-thousand-dollar investment...
“我们可以赚到5万来分”
we can make 50,000 distributing."
所以他们不能抵抗
So they can't resist.
我想要把它作为一门生意控制好，保持正派
I want to control it as a business...to keep it respectable.
我不要它接近学校
I don't want it near schools.
我不要把它卖给孩子
I don't want it sold to children.
那是丧良心的[意大利语]
That's an infamia.
在我的城市，我们会把买卖保持在黑人，有色人种当中
In my city, we'll keep the traffic in the dark people, the colored.
他们反正是动物，所以让他们灵魂堕落吧
They're animals anyway, so let them lose their souls.
我早希望我们能到这里来，一起讲讲道理
I hoped that we could come here and reason together.
身为一个讲道理的人，我愿意做任何事…
As a reasonable man, I'm willing to do whatever's necessary to...
为这些问题找到一个和平的解决方案
find a peaceful solution to these problems.
那我们就都同意了
Then we are agreed.
毒品买卖将会获准，但要有控制
The traffic in drugs will be permitted but controlled.
唐・柯利昂尼会给我们东部的保护
Don Corleone will give us protection in the east...
这样就有和平
and there will be the peace.
但我必须有唐・柯利昂尼的直接担保
But I must have strict assurance from Corleone.
随着时间推移，他的地位变得更强大…
As time goes by and his position becomes stronger...
他会不会意图报血仇？
will he attempt any individual vendetta?
你看，我们这全是讲理的人
Look, we are all reasonable men here.
我们不必给出保证，好像我们是律师
We don't have to give assurances as if we were lawyers.
你说到复仇
You talk about vengeance.
复仇会把你儿子带回给你吗？
Is vengeance gonna bring your son back to you?
或把我的儿子给我？
Or my boy to me?
我放弃为我儿子复仇
I forego the vengeance of my son.
但我有自私的理由
But I have selfish reasons.
我最小的儿子，被迫离开这个国家
My youngest son...was forced to leave this country...
因为索洛佐这件事
because of this Sollozzo business.
好吧，我必须做出各种安排，把他安全带回来
All right. And I have to make arrangements to bring him back here safely.
澄清所有这些错误的指控
cleared of all these false charges.
但我是个迷信的人
But I'm a superstitious man.
如果有什么不幸意外落在他身上
And if some unlucky accident should befall him--
如果他被一个警官开枪打中脑袋
if he should get shot in the head by a police officer...
或如果他在自己的牢房里上吊
or if he should hang himself in his jail cell...
或如果他被一道闪电击中
of if he's struck by a bolt of lightening--
那我将怪罪这房间里的某些人
then I'm going to blame some of the people in this room.
那是我不会原谅的
And that I do not forgive.
但是，除此之外…
But that aside...
我可以说我发誓，以我孙子的灵魂
let me say that I swear... on the souls of my grandchildren...
我不会是打破我们今天和议的人
that I will not be the one to break the peace we've made here today.
我跟见塔塔利亚的人会面时…
When I meet with the Tattaglia people...
要不要坚持那些毒品中间人 都没有前科？
should I insist that all these drug middlemen have clean records?
提出来即可，不要坚持
Mention it. Don't insist.
巴茨尼是个不用说也明白的人
Barzini is a man who'll know that without being told.
你是说塔塔利亚
You mean Tattaglia.
塔塔利亚是个拉皮条的
Tattaglia's a pimp.
他根本不可能干掉桑提诺
He never could've outfought Santino.
但我直到今天以前并不知道，这事……
But I didn't know until this day that it was...
一直是巴茨尼做的
Barzini all along.
来吧，南希
Come on, Nancy.
大家待在一起  布莱恩
Keep together, everyone. Brian?
好了，对了
Okay. All right.
你回来多久了？
How long have you been back?
我回来一年了
I've been back a year.
我觉得还要长
Longer than that, I think.
见到你真好，凯伊
It's good to see you, Kay.
我现在为我父亲做事，凯伊
I'm working for my father now, Kay.
他一直病着，病得很重
He's been sick.Very sick.
可你并不像他，迈克尔
But you're not like him, Michael.
我以为你不会变成你父亲那样的人
I thought you weren't going to become a man like your father.
那是你告诉我的
That's what you told me.
我父亲跟其他有权的人没有区别
My father's no different than any other powerful man.
那种对其他人负有责任的人
Any man who's responsible for other people.
像是参议员或总统
Like a senator or a president.
你知道你说得多天真吗？
Do you know how naive you sound?
为什么？
Why?
参议员和总统不会派人杀人
Senators and presidents don't have men killed.
是谁天真，凯伊？
Who's being naive, Kay?
凯伊，我父亲做事的方法已经过时，结束了
Kay, my father's way of doing things is over. It's finished.
他也知道这一点
Even he knows that.
我是说 在五年柯利昂尼家族会完全合法化
I mean, in five years the Corleone family is going to be completely legitimate.
相信我，有关我的公事，我只能告诉你这些
Trust me. That's all I can tell you about my business.
凯伊
Kay
迈克尔，你为什么要来这里？
Michael, why did you come here?
为什么？
Why?
你想要我怎样？这么长时间连电话也没有，也没有信
What do you want with me after all this time without even calling or writing?
我来是因为我需要你
I came here because I need you.
因为我关心你
Because I care for you.
- 请别说了，迈克尔  - 因为…
- Please stop it, Michael. -Because...
我想要你嫁给我
I want you to marry me.
- 太迟了，太迟了…  - 求你，凯伊
- It's too late. - Please, Kay.
你要我做什么我都愿意，任何事，来弥补…
I'll do anything you ask, anything to make up
我俩过去发生的事
for what's happened to us.
因为那很重要，凯伊
Because that's important, Kay.
因为重要的是…
Because what's important is that...
我们拥有彼此
we have each other.
是我们要共度一生
That we have a life together.
是我们要有孩子
That we have children--
我们的孩子
our children.
凯伊
Kay.
我需要你
I need you...
而且我爱你
and I love you.
巴茨尼的人楔进我的地盘
Barzini's people chisel my territory...
而我们却什么也没做
and we do nothing about it.
很快我在布鲁克林就连挂帽子的地方都没有了
Pretty soon, there won't be one place in Brooklyn I can hang my hat.
耐心点
Just be patient.
我不是求你帮忙，麦克，只是不想受掣肘
I'm not askin' you for help, Mike. I just take off the handcuffs.
耐心点
Be patient.
我们必须保护自己
We gotta protect ourselves.
给我个机会招募一些新人
Give me a chance to recruit some new men.
不
No.
我不想给巴茨尼借口来开战
I don't wanna give Barzini an excuse to start fighting.
麦克，你错了
Mike, you're wrong.
唐・柯利昂尼
Don Corleone,
你曾说过 要让我跟泰西欧有一天能自立门户
you once said the day would come when Tessio and me could form our own family.
今天以前 我绝对没想过
Till today, I would never think of it.
我要求你的批准
I must ask your permission.
现在迈克尔是家族首领
Well, Michael is now head of the family and
如果他准许了，我就祝福你
if he gives his permission, then you have my blessing.
等我们搬到内华达州后
After we make the move to Nevada...
你就可以从柯利昂尼家族分出去，自立门户
you can break off from the Corleone family and go on your own.
等我们搬到内华达州之后
After we make the move to Nevada.
那会有多久？
How long will that be?
6个月
Six months.
原谅我，教父，但你这一走…
Forgive me, Godfather, but with you gone...
我跟彼得迟早会被巴茨尼捏在手中
me and Pete'll come under Barzini's thumb sooner or later.
我恨那该死的巴茨尼
And I hate that goddamn Barzini.
6个月的时间，剩不下什么给我们建设了
In six months' time, there won't be nothing left to build on.
你们对我的判断有信心吗？
You have faith in my judgment?
- 是的  - 你们对我忠心吗？
- Yes.  - Do I have your loyalty?
是的，一向如此，教父
Yes, always, Godfather.
那就当迈克尔的朋友吧
Then be a friend to Michael...
照他说的做
and do as he says.
现在有些事仍在磋商…
There are things being negotiated now...
将会解决你们的所有问题，解答所有疑问
that are gonna solve all your problems and answer all your questions.
现在我只能告诉你们这些
That's all I can tell you now.
卡洛，你在内华达长大
Carlo, you grew up in Nevada.
等我们搬过去的时候，你会是我的左右手
When we make our move there, you're gonna be my right-hand man.
汤姆・黑根不再做Consigliere了
Tom Hagen's no longer consigliere.
他将会是我们在维加斯的律师
He's gonna be our lawyer in Vegas.
对汤姆没有不满，但我想要这样
That's no reflection on Tom, but that's the way I want it.
再说，要是我需要什么建议，有比我父亲更好的Consigliere吗？Consigliere
Besides, if I ever need help who's a better consigliere than my father?
就这些
That's it.
好的
All right.
- 谢谢，爸爸  - 我为你高兴，卡洛
- Thank you, Papa. - I'm happy for you, Carlo.
迈克尔…我为何出局了？
Michael...Why am I out?
你不适合当战时Consigliere
You're not a wartime consigliere.
随着我们这次转移，情况会变得棘手
Things may get rough with the move we're trying.
汤姆
Tom.
我跟迈克尔建议的
I advised Michael.
我从不认为你是个糟糕的Consigliere
I never thought you were a bad consigliere.
我认为…桑提诺是个糟糕的唐
I thought Santino was a bad Don...
愿他安息
rest in peace.
我对迈克尔完全信任，对你也是
Michael has all my confidence, as you do.
但是…
But...
要你不参与即将发生的事情 是有理由的
there are reasons why you must have no part of what is going to happen.
也许我能帮上忙
Maybe I could help.
你出局了，汤姆
You're out, Tom.
我无法不注意你脸的模样
I can't get over the way your face looks.
它看起来真的很棒
It really looks good.
这医生干得不错
This doctor did some job.
谁说服你去的，凯伊吗？
Who talked you into it, Kay?
喂喂喂，把它们留在这里
Hey, hey, wait. Leave them out here.
我们待会儿再处理它们
We'll deal with them later.
他累了，他要梳洗一下
He's tired. He wants to clean up.
好了，现在我来开门好吗？
All right, now, let me open the door, all right?
你好，麦克，欢迎光临拉斯维加斯
Hello, Mike. Welcome to Las Vegas.
全是为你准备的，小子
All for you, kid.
都是他的主意  对吧？
It was all his idea, right?
哦，你哥哥弗雷多…
Well, your brother, Freddy--
- 都是约翰尼…  - 女孩们来…
- It was Johnny--  - Girls here?
- 我就回来，你让她们别闲着  - 好，好的
- I'll be right back. You keep them occupied. - All right. Okay.
这才对
That a boy, huh?
你要什么都有，小子，都有
Anything you want, kid, anything.
那些女孩子是谁？
Who are the girls?
这得要你来搞清楚了
That's for you to find out.
把她们弄走，弗雷多
Get rid of them, Fredo
喂，麦克
Hey, Mike--
弗雷多，我是来办公事的，明天就走
Fredo, I'm here on business. I leave tomorrow.
现在把她们弄走
Now, get rid of them.
我累了  把乐队也弄走
I'm tired. Get rid of the band too.
喂，走吧，来吧，走人，走吧
Hey, just take off. Come on, take off. Let's go, come on.
喂，结束了，安杰洛，结束了
Hey, that's it. Angelo, that's it.
来，走吧
Come on, let's go.
喂，快点，赶紧走！
Hey, come on! Scram!
走吧，亲，走了
Scram! Come on, honey. Let's go.
我不知道  约翰尼
I don't know, Johnny.
我不知道他是怎么回事，对不起
I don't know what the hell's the matter with him, I'm sorry.
没关系，没事的，弗雷迪
It's all right. It's all right, Freddy.
我不知道，他大概累了
I don't know. He's tired, he's hot.
莫・格林怎么回事？
What happened to Moe Greene?
他说他有别的事
He said he had some business.
他说等派对开始时  给他打个电话
He said give him a call...when the party started.
那就给他打个电话
Well, give him a call.
约翰尼，你好吗？
Johnny, how are you?
你好，迈克尔，真高兴再见到你
Hello, Michael, nice to see you again.
我们全都以你为傲
We're all proud of you.
谢谢，迈克尔
Thanks, Mike.
坐下，约翰尼，我要跟你谈谈
Sit down,Johnny. I want to talk to you.
唐也以你为傲，约翰尼
The Don's proud of you too, Johnny.
我的一切都是欠他的
Well, I owe it all to him.
他知道你有多感恩
Well, he knows how grateful you are.
所以…他想请你帮个忙
That's why he'd like to ask a favor of you.
麦克，我能做些什么？
Mike, what can I do?
柯利昂尼家族在考虑放弃橄榄油生意上的全部投资
The Corleone family is thinking of giving up all its interests in the olive oil business
在这里安顿下来
settling out here.
莫・格林会卖给我们 他在赌场及酒店的所有股份
Now, Moe Greene will sell us his share of the casino and hotel...
这样它能完全为家族所有
so it can be completely owned by the family.
- 汤姆  - 麦克，这你确定吗？
- Tom.  - Mike, are you sure about that?
莫热爱这门生意
Moe loves the business.
他从未对我提过要卖掉它的事
He never said nothin' to me about sellin'.
我会提个他无法拒绝的条件
I'll make him an offer he can't refuse.
你看，约翰尼…
See,Johnny...
你看，我们估计娱乐表演会是很强的因素
See, we figure that entertainment will be a big factor
把赌客拉进到赌场来
in drawing gamblers to the casino.
我们希望你签个合约 一年登台五次
We hope you'll sign a contract to appear five times a year.
也许还能…劝说一些你在电影圈的朋友，也这么做
Perhaps convince some of your friends in the movies to do the same.
我指望你了
We're counting on you.
当然，麦克
Sure, Mike.
为我的教父我什么都肯做，这你知道
I'll do anything for my godfather. You know that.
好
Good.
嘿，麦克，各位好，大家都在这里
Hey, Mike. Hello, fellas. Everybody's here.
弗雷迪，汤姆…
Freddy, Tom.
- 见到你真好，麦克  - 你好吗，莫？
Good to see you, Mike. How are you, Moe?
好，你要的都齐了吗？
All right. You got everything you want?
厨师给你做特餐
The chef cooked for you special,
舞蹈能让你咋舌，你的信用蛮好的
the dancers will kick your tongue out and your credit is good.
弄点筹码给房间里每个人，让他们到场子里去玩玩
Draw chips for everybody in the room so they can play on the house.
我的信用好到够买下你吗？
My credit good enough to buy you out?
买下我？
Buy me out?
这个赌场，这家酒店
The casino. The hotel.
柯利昂尼家族想买下你全部的生意
The Corleone family wants to buy you out.
柯利昂尼家族想买下我？
The Corleone family wants to buy me out?
不，我买下你们，你们买不下我
No, I buy you out. You don't buy me out.
你的赌场赔钱了
Your casino loses money.
也许我们能做得更好些
Maybe we can do better.
你以为我滑下顶峰了，迈克尔？
You think I'm skimming off the top, Mike?
你运气不好
You're unlucky.
你这该死的意大利佬真把我逗乐了
You goddamn guineas really make me laugh.
你们有难时 我帮你们忙收留弗雷迪
I do you a favor and take Freddy in when you're having a bad time.
现在你想把我挤走
Then you try to push me out!
等一下
Wait a minute.
你收留弗雷迪，是因为柯利昂尼家族给你的赌场财政支援
You took Freddy in because the Corleone family bankrolled your casino...
因为海岸的莫伦纳里家族
because the Molinari family on the coast...
保证他的安全
guaranteed his safety.
现在我们谈的是生意，我们来谈谈生意
Now, we're talkin' business. Let's talk business.
好，我们来谈生意，麦克
Let's talk business, Mike.
首先，你们都完了
First of all, you're all done.
柯利昂尼家族再也没有那么强大了
The Corleone family don't even have that kind of muscle anymore.
教父生病了，对吧？
The Godfather's sick, right?
你们被巴茨尼及其它家族 赶出了纽约
You're getting chased out of New York...by Barzini and the other families.
你以为是怎么回事？
What do you think is gonna on?
你以为能到我的酒店来接管？
You think you can come to my hotel and take over?
我和巴茨尼谈过
I talked to Barzini.
我可以跟他做一笔交易，而且仍然保留我的酒店
I can make a deal with him and still keep my hotel.
所以你就当众掌掴我哥哥吗？
Is that why you slapped my brother around in public?
哦，不，那不算什么，麦克
Oh, no, that was nothin', Mike.
那个…莫那样做没别的意思
Now, now...Moe didn't mean nothin' by that.
当然他时不时会发火，但是…
Sure he flies off the handle once in a while, but...
但莫和我是好朋友，对吧，莫？
but Moe and me, we're good friends, right, Moe?
我要经营生意
I got a business to run.
我有时候得严厉些，是为了好好经营
I gotta kick asses sometimes to make it run right.
我们有点小争执，弗雷迪跟我
We had a little argument, Freddy and I
所以我不得不纠正他
so I had to straighten him out.
你纠正我哥哥？
You straightened my brother out?
他一次搞两个鸡尾酒女郎
He was banging cocktail waitresses two at a time!
赌客在桌上要不到酒
Players couldn't get a drink on the table.
你有什么毛病？
What's wrong with you?
我明天动身去纽约
I leave for New York tomorrow.
考虑一个价钱吧
Think about a price.
婊子养的
Son of a bitch.
你知道我是谁吗？我是莫・格林
Do you know who I am? I'm Moe Greene.
我进家族时你还在跟啦啦队长约会
I made my bones when you were going out with cheerleaders.
等等，莫，我有个主意
Wait a minute, Moe. Moe, I got an idea.
汤姆
Tom
汤姆，你是Consigliere
Tom, you're the consigliere.
- 你可以跟唐说说，你可以解释…  - 等一下
-You can talk to the Don. You can explain...-Just a minute.
唐已经半退休了，麦克现在负责家族事务
The Don is semiretired. Mike is in charge of the business now.
你有什么话说，跟迈克尔说吧
If you have anything to say, say it to Michael.
麦克，你不能到拉斯维加斯来
Mike! You don't come to Las Vegas
跟莫・格林那种人那样说话
and talk to a man like Moe Greene like that!
弗雷多
Fredo
你是我哥哥，而且我爱你
You're my older brother, and I love you.
但是再也别站在外人一边 反对家族了
But don't ever take sides with anyone...against the family again...
永远
ever.
我得先去看我父亲和他的手下
I have to see my father and his people.
所以别等我吃晚饭了
So have dinner without me.
迈克尔
Oh, Michael.
这个周末我们出去
This weekend we'll go out.
我们到城里去，看电影吃饭，我保证
We'll go to the city. We'll see a show and have dinner. I promise.
迈克尔
Michael.
迈克尔，你妹妹有事想问你
Michael, your sister wants to ask you something.
- 让她来问  - 不，她害怕
- Let her ask. - No, she's afraid to.
康妮和卡洛 想要你当他们孩子的教父
Connie and Carlo want you to be godfather to their little boy.
- 看情况吧  - 你会当吗？
- We'll see. - Will you?
让我考虑一下，看情况吧，来吧
Let me think about it. We'll see. Come on.
所以…
So...
巴茨尼会先一步对付你
Barzini will move against you first.
他会与一个你完全信任的人设计一次会面
He'll set up a meeting with someone that you absolutely trust...
保证你的安全
guaranteeing your safety.
然后在会面时，你会被暗杀
And at that meeting, you'll be assassinated.
我越来越比以前爱喝了
I like to drink wine more than I used to.
总之，我喝得更多了
Anyway, I'm drinking more.
对你有好处，爸爸
It's good for you, Pop.
我不知道
I don't know.
你妻子和孩子，你跟他们快乐吧？
Your wife and children, are you happy with them?
非常快乐
Very happy.
那就好
That's good.
希望你不介意 我一直在谈巴茨尼的事
I hope you don't mind the way I... I keep going over this Barzini business.
不，一点也不
No, not at all.
这是个老习惯
It's an old habit.
我一辈子努力不要粗心
I spent my life tryin' not to be careless.
女人和小孩能够粗心大意，但男人不行
Women and children can be careless, but not men.
- 你儿子怎么样？  - 他很好
- How's your boy? - He's good.
你知道他的样子一天天更像你了
You know, he looks more like you every day.
他比我聪明
He's smarter than I am.
三岁就能看漫画了
Three years old, he can read the funny papers.
他会看漫画
He reads the funny papers.
我要你安排一个电话公司的人
I want you to arrange to have a telephone man...
检查每一个进出这里的电话
check all the calls that go in and out of here.
- 我已经做了，爸  - 可能是任何人  - 爸，我已经处理了
- I did it already. - Could be anyone. - Pa, I took care of that.
哦，对，我忘了
Oh, that's right. I forgot.
怎么回事？
What's the matter?
是什么困扰着你？
What's bothering you?
我会应付的
I'll handle it.
我跟你说过我能应付，我会的应付的
I told you I can handle it, I'll handle it.
我知道桑提诺一定会经历这一切…
I knew that Santino was gonna have to go through all this...
还有弗雷多
and Fredo--
弗雷多他…
Fredo was--
但我从未…我从未想要你来
But I never...I never wanted this for you.
我工作了一辈子，我不会辩解…
I worked my whole life-- I don't apologize--
我照顾了我的家人
to take care of my family...
而且我拒绝当个傻瓜…
and I refused to be a fool...
随那些大人物的提线起舞
dancing on a string held by all those big shots.
我不会辩解，那是我的人生，但是我以为…
I don't apologize. That's my life. But I thought that--
等到了你的时代，你会成为掌握提线的人
that when it was your time... you would be the one to hold the strings.
参议员柯利昂尼
Senator Corleone.
州长柯利昂尼之类
Governor Corleone. Something.
另一个大亨[意大利语]
Another pezzonovante.
唉…
Well...
时间还是不够，迈克尔，时间不够
Just wasn't enough time, Michael. Wasn't enough time.
我们会做到的，爸
We'll get there, Pop.
我们会做到的
We'll get there.
听好了…
Now, listen,
不管谁来邀你去和巴茨尼开会
whoever comes to you with this Barzini meeting...
他就是叛徒
he's the traitor.
别忘了这一点
Don't forget that.
我能给浇这个吗？
Can I water these?
好的，可以
Yeah. That's fine.
这边来，这边来
Over here. Over here.
小心点，你弄洒了，你弄洒了
Be careful. You're spilling it.
安东尼，过来，过来…
Anthony, come here.
过来
Come here.
来，对了，我们把它放在这里
Go ahead. That's right. We'll put it right there.
我给你看样东西，来
I'll show you something. Come on.
来
Come on.
你站在这里
Now, you stand there.
橙子给我
Give me an orange!
好了，没事
All right, no.
这是新把戏
That's a new trick.
你跑进去，跑进去
You run in there. Run in there.
- 你在哪？  - 谁？
- Where are you? - Who?
迈克尔  能借一步说话吗？
Mike, can I have a minute?
巴茨尼想要安排一次会议
Barzini wants to arrange a meeting.
他说我们可以纠正所有问题
He says we can straighten any of our problems out.
- 你跟他谈过？  - 是的
- You talked to him? - Yeah.
我能安排安全事宜
I can arrange security...
在我的地盘上
on my territory.
好吗？
All right?
- 好  - 好的
- All right. - All right.
你知道他们会怎么攻击你吗？
Do you know how they're gonna come at you?
他们安排在布鲁克林开会
They're arranging a meeting in Brooklyn.
泰西欧的地盘
Tessio's ground...
在那里我会安全
where I'll be safe.
我一直以为会是克里门萨，而不是泰西欧
I always thought it would've been Clemenza, not Tessio.
这是聪明的一步，泰西欧一向更聪明
It's the smart move. Tessio was always smarter.
但我会等待
But I'm gonna wait.
等到洗礼之后
After the baptism.
我已经决定当康妮小孩的教父了
I've decided to be godfather to Connie's baby.
然后我再去见唐・巴茨尼
And then I'll meet with Don Barzini...
还有塔塔利亚
and Tattaglia...
所有五大家族的首领
all the heads of the five families.
阿门
迈克尔，你相信上帝吗？
Michael, do you believe in God...
全能的天父，天地的创造者？
the Father Almighty, creator of Heaven and Earth?
我相信
I do.
你相信耶稣基督，他的独子，我们的主吗？
Do you believe in Jesus Christ, his only Son, our Lord?
我相信
I do.
你相信圣灵，神圣的天主教堂吗？
Do you believe in the holy Ghost, the holy Catholic Church?
我相信
I do.
迈克尔・弗兰西斯・里奇
Michael Francis Rizzi,
你弃绝撒旦吗？
do you renounce Satan?
我弃绝他
I do renounce him.
以及他所有的作为吗？
And all his works?
我弃绝它们
I do renounce them.
以及他所有的浮华？
And all his pomps?
我弃绝它们
I do renounce them.
迈克尔・里奇
Michael Rizzi,
你愿意受洗吗？
will you be baptized?
我愿意
I will.
迈克尔・里奇，平平安安
Michael Rizzi, go in peace.
愿主与你同在，阿门
And may the Lord be with you. Amen.
凯伊
Kay.
这是你的教父
This is your godfather.
卡洛
Carlo.
什么？
What?
不能去维加斯了
Can't go to Vegas.
临时有要事，大家得跟我们留下
Something's come up. Everybody's gonna have to leave with us.
- 哦，麦克，这是我们第一次一起度假  - 喂，康妮，拜托
- Oh, Mike, it's our first vacation together. - Hey, Connie, please.
- 你要我怎么做  - 回家去等我电话，有要事
- What do you wanna do? - Go back to the house. Wait for my call. It's important.
好的
All right.
我只需一两天
I'll only be a couple of days.
旅途愉快，妈
Have a nice trip, Mama.
我们上路去布鲁克林了
We're on our way to Brooklyn.
我希望麦克今晚能给我们谈个好交易
I hope Mike can get us a good deal tonight.
他一定会的
I'm sure he will.
萨尔、汤姆
Sal, Tom,
老板说他另外坐车来
the boss says he'll come in a separate car.
说叫你们先走
He says for you two to go on ahead.
见鬼，他不能那么做
Hell, he can't do that.
- 弄乱了我所有的安排  - 他是这么说的
-It screws up all my arrangements. -That's what he said.
我也不能去了，萨尔
I can't go either, Sal.
告诉麦克这只是生意
Tell Mike it was only business.
我一直都喜欢他
I always liked him.
他会理解的
He understands that.
抱歉，萨尔
Excuse me, Sal.
汤姆，你能帮我脱身吗？
Tom, can you get me off the hook?
- 看在老交情的份上  - 我办不到，萨利
- For old times' sake. - Can't do it, Sally.
你得为桑提诺负责，卡洛
You have to answer for Santino, Carlo.
- 麦克，你全搞错了  - 你替巴茨尼的人挑拨了桑尼
-Mike, you got it all wrong. -You fingered Sonny for the Barzini people.
你对我妹妹演的那场小闹剧
That little farce you played with my sister.
你以为那能骗得过柯利昂尼家的人吗？
Did you think that could fool a Corleone?
麦克，我是清白的
Mike, I'm innocent.
我以孩子们起誓
I swear on the kids.
- 求你，麦克，别这样对我  - 坐下
- Please, Mike, don't do this to me. - Sit down there.
麦克，别这样对我，求你
Mike, don't do this to me, please.
巴茨尼死了
Barzini's dead.
菲利普・塔塔利亚也是
So is Phillip Tattaglia...
莫・格林
Moe Greene
斯特拉奇
Strachi...
科尼奥
Cuneo.
今天我解决家族全部事务
Today I settle all family business,
所以别跟我说你是清白的，卡洛
so don't tell me you're innocent, Carlo.
承认你所做的
Admit what you did.
给他一杯酒
Get him a drink.
说吧
Come on.
别害怕，卡洛
Don't be afraid, Carlo.
得了，你以为我会让我妹妹当寡妇？
Come on, you think I'd make my sister a widow?
我是你儿子的教父，卡洛
I'm godfather to your son, Carlo.
来，喝吧，喝吧
Go ahead, drink. Drink.
不，卡洛，你退出家族生意，这是给你的惩罚
Now, Carlo, you're out of the family business. That's your punishment.
你结束了，我送你上飞机去维加斯
You're finished. I'm putting you on a plane to Vegas.
汤姆
Tom.
我要你留在那边，明白吗？
I want you to stay there. Understand?
只是别告诉我你是清白的
Only don't tell me you're innocent...
因为那侮辱了我的智力
because it insults my intelligence.
让我非常生气
It makes me very angry.
现在，是谁接洽的你？
Now, who approached you?
塔塔利亚还是巴茨尼？
Tattaglia or Barzini?
是巴茨尼
It was Barzini.
好
Good.
外面有辆车等着 送你去机场
There's a car waiting for you outside to take you to the airport.
我会打电话给你妻子，告诉她说你坐哪班飞机
I'll call your wife, tell her what flight you're on.
- 请你，我…   - 快走，滚出我的视线
- Please, can I-- - Come on. Get out of my sight.
你好，卡洛
Hello, Carlo.
- 你别哭了行吗？  - 你想告诉我什么？
- Will you stop crying?  - What are you trying to tell me?
- 我想告诉你…  - 噢，妈妈，拜托
- I'm telling you you're wrong. - Mama, please!
迈克尔…
Michael.
- 怎么了？  - 他在哪儿？迈克尔！
- What is it?  - Where is he? Michael!
迈克尔，你这恶心的混蛋，你杀了我丈夫
Michael, you lousy bastard! You killed my husband!
你等到爸爸死后，没人能阻止你了
You waited until Papa died so nobody could stop you...
然后你就杀了他
and then you killed him!
你把桑尼的死怪罪于他
You blamed him for Sonny.
你一直都是，大家都是
You always did. Everybody did.
但你从未替我想过
But you never thought about me!
你从来不管我
You never gave a damn about me!
现在我该怎么办？
Now what am I gonna do?
康妮
Connie.
你以为他为什么要把卡洛留在林荫道？
Why do you think he kept Carlo at the mall?
一直以来他就知道自己要杀他
All the time he knew he was gonna kill him.
你还照样当我们孩子的教父
And you stood godfather to our baby.
你这恶心冷血的混蛋
You lousy, coldhearted bastard.
想知道跟卡洛一起 他杀了多少人吗？
Want to know how many men he had killed with Carlo?
看看报纸吧 看看报纸吧
Read the papers! Read the papers!
那就是你丈夫，那就是你丈夫…
That's your husband! That's your husband!
不！不！不！
No! No! No!
- 带她上楼  - 不！不！
- Take her upstairs. - No! No!
- 给她找个医生  - 老天
-Get her a doctor.-Oh, God!
她歇斯底里了
She's hysterical.
歇斯底里
Hysterical.
迈克尔，是真的吗？
Michael, is it true?
别问我的公事，凯伊
Don't ask me about my business, Kay.
是真的吗？
Is it true?
别过问我的公事
Don't ask me about my business.
- 不  - 够了
-No. -Enough!
好吧
All right.
只此一次
This one time.
就这一次我让你问我的公事
This one time, I'll let you ask me about my affairs.
是真的吗？
Is it true?
是吗？
Is it?
不是
No.
我想我俩都需要喝一杯
I guess we both need a drink, huh?
来
Come on.
唐・柯利昂尼
Don Corleone.